我们曾经是一个和平的超机械种族
We were once a peaceful race of intelligent, mechanical beings.
但后来却爆发了战争
But then came the war.
一方是为自由而战的汽车人
between the Autobots, who fought for freedom.
另一方则是妄图称霸的霸天虎
and the Decepticons, who dreamt of tyranny.
敌强我弱 敌众我寡
Overmatched and outnumbered,
我们必败无疑
our defeat was all but certain.
但就在战争临近尾声之时
But in the war's final days,
一艘汽车人飞船冲出了纷飞的战火
one Autobot ship escaped the battle.
飞船上载着一批秘密货物
It was carrying a secret cargo,
它本可以改变我们母星的命运
which would have changed our planet's fate.
那是最后的拼死一搏
A desperate mission.
承载着我们最后的希望
Our final hope.
而这希望...也破灭了
A hope that vanished.
(1961年 新墨西哥州 VLA射电天文台)
一个在那里 一个在这里
One over there. One up there.
还有一个在这里
And one more down there.
有什么收获?
What you got?
探测到撞击
Impact detected.
确认发生撞击
We have impact confirmed.
确认撞击
Contact.
于格林威治时间20点50分
at 2250 GMT.
什么?
What?
马上给我接通国防部长
Get me SecDef on the phone right away.
(紧急：跟踪到深空轨迹 探测到月面撞击)
(五角大楼 国家安全指挥部)
麦克·纳马拉部长 总统先生在等您
Mr. McNamara, the President is expecting you.
- 让鲍比进来 - 是的 总统先生
- Get Bobby in here. - Mr. President,
最高机密
designation, top secret.
有一艘不明飞行物在在月球上坠落
We believe a UFO has crashed into the Moon.
苏联人应该也在调查此事
We think the Russians are onto it as well.
命令航天局 要动用一切力量
Well, then you tell NASA to move heaven and earth.
我们得登上月球
We need to get to the moon.
我们得实现一次载人探月行动
We're going to attempt a manned mission.
航天局认为这得花上5年
NASA said it would take five years.
必须抢在苏联人之前登月
You get there before the Russians.
我相信我国人民能够齐聚一心全力以赴 达成这个目标...
I believe that this nation should commit itself to achieving the goal.
- 15秒 - ...即在1970年以前
- Fifteen seconds. - ...before this decade is out.
人类将乘坐宇宙飞船登陆月球
of landing a man on the moon.
并且安全返回地球
and returning him safely to the Earth.
启动发射程序
Ignition sequence start.
5...4...3...
Five, four, three.
2...
two...
One.
全部引擎工作正常
All engines running.
发射 已经发射
Liftoff. We have a liftoff.
时间是9点32分
Thirty-two minutes past the hour.
阿波罗11号发射升空
Liftoff on Apollo 11.
阿姆斯特朗报告 阿波罗11号飞行轨道正确
Neil Armstrong reporting Apollo 11 on proper heading.
阿波罗11号开始了旅程
Apollo 11 is on the way, riding that.
乘着土星5号运载火箭喷射出的长长烈焰
pillar of flame from the Saturn V out there,
奔向了25万英里之外
250, 000 miles away,
月球正在那里静候着人类的首次造访
where the moon is waiting for man 's first arrival.
这里是休斯顿 现在准备降落 完毕
Houston, you're a go for landing. Over.
40英尺 下降2.5英尺
Forty feet, down two and a half.
从表面上看都是灰尘
Picking up some dust.
30英尺 下降2.5英尺
Thirty feet, two and a half down.
已经能看到咱们登月舱的影子了
Faint shadow.
收到 请指示
Capcom, flight.
向前4英尺 向右漂移一点点
Four forward. Drifting to the right a little.
下降0.5英尺
Down a half.
轻轻降落
Contact light.
好了 关闭引擎
Okay, engine stop.
休斯顿 到达静海基地
Houston, tranquility base here.
小鹰号登月舱已经着陆
The Eagle has landed.
收到着陆讯号 小鹰号
We copy you down, Eagle.
你们把大家的脸都快憋青了
You got a bunch of guys about to turn blue.
总算能松口气了
We're breathing again.
大约有4亿人正在观看今日的直播
Perhaps 400 million persons are watching this broadcast today.
见证这一时代最伟大的成就
of the greatest event in our time.
这也是铭载史册的一大壮举
and one of the great events of all recorded history.
我下到了梯子的底部
I'm at the foot of the ladder.
现在走下了登月舱
Okay, I'm gonna step off the LEM now.
这是我个人的一小步
That's one small step for man,
但却是人类的一大步
one giant leap for mankind.
- 准备好了没? - 好了 长官
- Are we good? - Yes, sir.
转到1092非正式频道...
Unofficial time on the first step, 1092....
阿波罗11号 这里是休斯顿 完毕
Apollo 11? This is Houston, over.
小鹰号 我们遇到了讯号干扰
Eagle, we're gettinga signal interference.
你们听到了吗?
Do you copy?
刚刚得到证实 与阿波罗11号的联系暂时出现中断
We now have had confirmation of loss of signal from the Apollo 11.
阿波罗11号此刻正在月球的背面
The Apollo 11 is, at the moment, on the far side of the moon.
尼尔 你正在月球的背面
Neil, you are dark on the rock.
开始执行任务
Mission is a go.
我们有21分钟
We have 21 minutes.
请原地待命 倒计时3分45秒
Please stand by, 3 minutes and 45 seconds and counting.
我的天啊
My God.
好像是张巨大的金属面孔
It's some sort of giant metal face.
天啊
Jesus.
控制中心 我们已进入飞船内部
Control, we are inside the ship.
船体受损严重
Extensive damage.
难以对飞船进行全面检查
Way too big to check the entire ship.
这里一片死寂 休斯顿
Everything's dead in here, Houston.
没有任何生命迹象
No signs of life anywhere.
这些东西巨大无比
These things are massive.
收到
We copy.
你们的氧气还能维持7分钟
You've got seven minutes on your oxygen.
宇宙中并不只有我们 对吗?
We are not alone after all, are we?
没错 长官
No, sir.
我们并不是唯一的
We're not alone.
请讲 总统先生
Go ahead, Mr. President.
你们好 尼尔和巴兹
Hello, Neil and Buzz.
我正在白宫椭圆形办公室里给你们打电话
I'm talking to you by telephone from the Oval Room at the White House.
这绝对是一段将要载入史册的通话
And this certainly has to be the most historic telephone call ever made.
我们的自豪之情 我难以言表
I just can't tell you how proud we all are of you.
对每一位美国人来说 这都是此生中最为骄傲的一天
For every American, this has to be the proudest day of our lives.
因为你们的伟大壮举...
Because of what you have done....
我们已降落在海面上
We have splashdown.
...太空成为了人类世界的一部分
.... the heavens have become a part of man 's world.
这宝贵的一刻
For one priceless moment.
将会永远铭载人类史册
in the whole history of man.
全世界的人们此刻心连心
all the people on this Earth are truly one.
为你们的壮举而感到骄傲
One in their pride in what you have done.
这鼓舞着我们要加倍努力
It inspires us to redouble our efforts.
维护地球的和平与安宁
to bring peace and tranquility to Earth.
《变形金刚3：月黑之时》
我的英雄 该醒醒啦
My hero needs to wake up.
那是什么?
What is that?
是你的新幸运兔
This is your new lucky bunny.
这是个美好的愿望 卡莉
It's a beautiful thought, Carly,
不过并不是兔子全身都带着好运
but I don't think it's the whole bunny that's lucky.
这只有这一块地方
You see, it's just this section here.
只有兔脚这里才会带来好运
You see, it's just the rabbit foot that's lucky.
好吧 这只是个开运魔法
Well, it's just a good luck charm.
能让你积极向上起来
To help you think positive?
今天很重要
Today's important.
快点 起床吧
Come on, get up.
- 嘿 系那条领带比较帅 - 好
- Hey, wear that nice tie. - Yeah.
要我留午饭钱吗?
You need any money for lunch?
不 我不需要午饭钱了
No, I don't need any money for lunch.
昨天的还剩点
I have money from yesterday's lunch.
你喜欢这样 不是吗?
You love it, don't you?
我是你的美国小玩偶
I'm just your American boy toy.
是情人兼玩偶
A lover boy toy.
你知道这有多郁闷 我两次拯救世界
You know how demoralizing it is to have saved the world twice.
居然还得低声下气地去找工作?
and still be groveling for a job?
公众可不知道你拯救过世界 山姆
People don't know you saved the world, Sam.
但我知道 我相信你
I mean, I do. I believe you.
政府既然知情 就应该在华盛顿给我找份差事
The government knows. I mean, they could hook me up with a job right here in D. C.
我应该去跟汽车人共事
I mean, I should be working with the Autobots,
否则就太不公平了
otherwise it's not fair.
拜托 他们已经供你上了大学
Come on, they paid for your college.
总统还给你颁发了英雄勋章呢
The President gave you a hero medal.
谢谢你 山姆 干得好
Thank you, man. Great job.
这对我来说真是太酷了
That's the coolest thing that ever happened to me.
好了 小伙子们
All right, guys.
看这是什么
What the fuck!
哇哦
Wow.
而且 我记得那天还有更精彩的情节
And, as I recall, that wasn't even the highlight of your day.
- 大使先生 给 - 英国大使馆 你们是下一个
- Mr. Ambassador, here. - British Embassy, you're up next.
不 你不能戴着它
No, you don't wear it.
看 你必须放在...
See, you've gotta...
盒子里
The box.
我就是想戴戴嘛
I couldn't, even if I wanted to.
把它放进盒子 好吗?
You're supposed to leave it in the box, right?
放进去别动 瞧这盒子真漂亮
You keep it in this. What a gorgeous box.
对 没错 我的勋章
Oh, yeah. My medal.
知道是谁给我的吗?
You know who gave that to me?
谁?
Who?
- 博图士 - 哦
- POUTS. - Oh.
美国总统
President of the United States.
宝贝 不是每个人都能找到工作的
Babe, it's hard for everybody to get a job.
我没有时间了
I don't have time.
我爸妈开着房车环游世界
You see, my parents are gonna be here in a week.
下星期就要来咱们这里了
on their road trip Partybus World Tour.
我爸来了之后 要是看到我没工作
If my dad gets here and I don't have a job,
肯定会赏我耳光的 你知道 我得行动了
he's gonna spank me. You know, it's go time for me.
那好吧 今晚我给你安排个工作
All right, tonight, I'll give you a job.
给我做一顿美妙的浪漫大餐
Romance me with a nice dinner.
然后 我再多给你一点小费
and...maybe you can get that bonus.
- 喔... - 啊...哦...
- Wo... - Ah... Oh...
- 真好看 - 把他弄出去
- Good looking. - Get him out of here.
不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no.
哦 他真流氓
Oh, he's gross!
身材真好
She's good.
但他们流落到了这里 得有人照顾他们
But they're stranded here. Somebody's got to watch out for them.
昨天它还钻进了我的内衣抽屉
Yesterday, that one was in my underwear drawer.
研究一下嘛 顺便大饱眼福
Did research. Looking real good, too.
- 你还真打我啊 - 我只想找个平凡的男朋友
- What are you hitting, huh? - I just want a normal boyfriend..
- 你爱的就是我这点 不是吗? - 抱怨鬼
- That's what you love about me, isn't it? - Crybaby.
我还没说过“爱”这个字吧
You know I don't have the word yet..
也许等你有能力分摊房租再说吧
Maybe a little bit closer when you can pay your half of the rent.
再见
Good-bye.
一下雨就害得我短路
Frinking shorting my circuits out here.
你太不厚道了
It's inhumane, what it is!
让我们住在阳台上的小盒子里
Make us live in a box...on a balcony,
跟那畜生待在一块
right next to a beast.
- 把我当成动物看待 - 闭嘴 行吗?
- Like a common animal! - Stop, okay?
你和你那丑哥们 未经允许不能进来
You and your creepy sidekick can't be in here without permission.
谁定的规矩 那个金发妞吗?
According to who, Miss Blondie Blonde?
起来 小狗狗
Get up, little doggie!
驾
Hah.
唷 小诸葛 你怎么样啊?
Yo, Brains, what's up?
还不错
Doing good.
啊 没意思 这集我看过了是斯巴克发疯的那集
Ah shoot, I'd seen this one. It's the one where Spock goes nuts.
山姆 我真不知道该怎么跟那妞相处
You know, Sam, I don't know about moving in with this chick.
是像上一任那样甩了咱们怎么办?
What if she dumps us like the last girl?
她凶巴巴的 我不喜欢她
She was mean. Didn't like her.
咱们现在可得同仇敌忾
Us guys got to stick together.
我们是一家人
We are family.
不 我们可不是一家人 你不过是外星难民
No, we are not family. You're a political refugee,
我好不容易才找了一个欣赏我的人
and I have finally found someone who appreciates me for me.
那你得告诉她 我们不是你的宠物
Well, you tell her that we're not your pets,
更不是你的玩具
and we're not your toys!
好吧 我们是高等的天才外星种族 只想找个家
All right? We're an advanced, geniusalien race just looking for a home.
- 我们可以停在这里 - 我觉得不该停
- Maybe it wasn't such a good idea. - Didn't have to stop.
拜托 他们还能怎样 拖走吗?
Come on. What're they going to do, tow it?
他在哪?
Where is he?
小山山
Sammy!
- 噢 别这样 这很搞笑 哈哈 - 山姆
- Oh, come on, that's funny. Ha ha. - Sam.
我想死你们了
I missed you guys so much.
不想才怪呢 你觉得这身如何?
Sure, you did. What do you think?
- 瞧你们 - 可爱吧?
- Look at that. - Cute.
- 看着很老 - 闭嘴
- You look old. - Stop it.
能看得出岁数来
Feel like I can see the end.
我喜欢你的小领带 嘿 我的准儿媳妇在哪?
I love your little tie. Hey, where's my girl?
- 我们漂亮的卡莉哪去了? - 她上班去了 妈妈
- Where's my beautiful Carly? - She's at work, Ma.
她找了份新工作
She's got a new job. You guys said.
我以为你们一周之后才来的
you were gonna be here in a week.
是21号 而不是11号 记得吗? 爹?
The 21st, not the 11th, Dad, remember?
我只负责把这车开过来
We just hauled ass in this thing.
- 我们快马加鞭赶过来的 - 这大家伙跑得飞快
- We stopped for gas. - This thing. The love tub, it flies.
噢 我们打扰你了没?
Oh, are we keeping you from something?
比如说 你的工作
Like, say, your job?
嗯 上班时间到了
Well, it's about time.
应该很着急吧
You had us worried.
呃 我有几个面试要去
Uh. I have job interviews.
哦 很好啊
Oh. That's good.
- 真杯具 - 别说了
- That sucks. - Stop it.
别这么消极嘛 爸爸
You don't have to be so negative, Dad.
咱们一家人好不容易在华盛顿团聚了
You're here with your son and your family.
- 应该是高兴的时候 - 真杯具你居然没工作
- I mean, it's a good time. - It sucks that you don't have a job.
- 有很多事可以做啊 对吧? - 就是
- Yeah, but there's good thingsto do here, too, right? - yeah.
对嘛 逛逛博物馆 看看纪念碑 好吗?
Right? Museums and monuments, okay?
- 晚上再见 - 我要把礼物收回
- I'll see you tonight. - I'm bagging the gift.
山姆 面试应该穿正式点的裤子
Sam, I think for an interview you should wear real pants.
你们应该天天都穿正式点的裤子
I think for life, you should wear real pants.
- 噢 大...大黄蜂这是怎么了? - 天啊
- Oh, wha... what happened to Bumble Bee? - Jesus.
他去执行任务了 我只好拿这个当替补
He's off on his missions. I had to get this for backup.
哦 连你的车也有工作 嗯?
Oh, your car has a job, huh?
别说了 它能变成什么?
Stop. What does it change into?
什么也不会变
It doesn't change into anything.
这就是件古董 妈
It's a collector's item, Ma.
我从地摊上淘来的 开几次就好 相信我
I got it for a steal. It just needs some work. Trust me.
这车挺可爱的 让我想起了大黄蜂
No, I think it's darling. It reminds me a lot of Bumblebee,
要是大黄蜂报废了大概就这个样子
if Bumblebee were a sad piece of shit.
来吧 我们送你去
Come on, we'll give you a ride!
自从我们到来之后我们的新家 地球
In the years since our arrival, our new home, Earth,
发生了许多变化
has seen much change.
能量检测仪保卫着每个城市
Energon detectors guard its cities now.
远程防御系统随时护卫领空
Long-range defense systems watch the skies.
(中东 非法核设施)
所以现在 我们也协助盟友们
So now we assist our allies,
解决人类间的冲突
in solving human conflicts.
阻止人类彼此伤害
to prevent mankind from bringing harm to itself.
是国防部长的车
The Defense Minister's car.
立即放行
Bisila.
哈哈 趴在地上 不许动 老实待着
Haha. on the ground, per favore! And stay there!
我们组成秘密分队 在全球各地执行各种任务
We work in secret teams on various missions around the globe.
同时 我们也在寻找宿敌...
And all the while we search for signs.
...卷土重来的蛛丝马迹
of our true enemies' return.
我是沃斯霍德 乌克兰能源部法律顾问
I am Voshkod, General Counsel with Ukrainian Department of Energy.
我国政府会否认我们之间存在这次谈话
My government will officially deny that we're having this conversation.
我们在一座废弃的核设施内有了意外发现
At one of our decommissioned facilities, a discovery was made,
恐怕是外星生物的痕迹
which I fear may be alien in nature.
那座核设施的名字叫“切尔诺贝利”
The facility's name is Chernobyl.
沃斯霍德先生
Mr. Voshkod.
自1986年起这里就成了一座空城
So, uninhabited since '86.
我听说两万年之内都不适宜人类居住
I hear it won't be livable again for another 20, 000 years?
至少两万年 乌克兰原本土壤肥沃 那真是场悲剧
At least. Ukraine was the most fertile land. It's a tragedy.
这边请
This way.
做好准备 只能待60分钟 注意各自的辐射量水平
Gear up! We have 60 minutes on the ground. Watch your radiation levels.
沃斯霍德先生 你的防护衣呢?
Mr. Voshkod, where's your protective gear?
你的防护衣在哪?
Where's your protective gear?
已经没必要了
It would not matter.
对我来说 死是迟早的事
For me, it's only a matter of time.
穿过这所学校
Through the school.
尤里会带你们下去 另外还有件事 上校
Yuri will take you below. And one other thing, Colonel.
别说出去 这里进行过能源实验
In private, there were some energy experiments.
哦 待会儿再说
Ho. It can wait.
继续前进 跟紧点
Keep moving. Stay tight.
这里 我们找到了 把灯拿来
Okay, right here. I think I found it.
指挥官 我们有画面了
Optimus, we got a visual.
我们发现了一个东西 被金属器械夹住了
Looks like the object's clamped in some kind of a metal harness.
这是什么?
What's this?
伙计们 这上面怎么有苏联太空竞赛计划的标志?
Guys! Why does this thing have Soviet space program markings on it?
- 史普尼克? - 有能量读数 长官
- Sputnik? - Energon readings, sir.
非常强烈
It's strong.
在我们下面
Below us.
来得很快
It's coming fast.
过来了 过来了
Contact, go there!
到上面去 快走 快 快
Get topside now! Move, move, move!
快走
Let's go!
准备 重武器准备
Weapons up! Heavy weapons up!
躲在我身后
Stay behind me!
快 快
move move.
擎天柱
Optimus!
快撤
Fall back!
它缠住我们了
It's circling around us!
它在我们侧面 快走
It bring our flank! come on.
准备重武器
Get the heavy weapon!
擎天柱
Optimus!
那是什么鬼东西?
What the hell was that thing?
那位...是震荡波
That is Shockwave.
他为什么要这个?
Why was he after this?
这不可能
It's impossible.
这是个引擎零件 来自一艘失踪已久的汽车人飞船
This is an engine part from a long lost Autobot ship.
与你合作很愉快
Pleasure working with you.
要去面试了 真让人兴奋
Interviews. This is so exciting.
甜心 你要口香糖吗?
Honey, do you want some gum?
每次你一紧张 口气就很重
Your breath gets really gnarly when you're nervous.
维特维奇先生
Mr. Witwicky?
在这 不用找了
Yeah. Search is over.
叫我惠特利好了
I'm Mr. Whitley.
先生...
Mr...
- 请问一下 还有别人吗? - 没有
- Is anybody else joining? - No.
没有?
No?
- 我能坐那里吗? - 最好别坐
- Want me to move right there, I'm moving right there. - I prefer not.
先生
Sensei.
- 准备好了吗? - 开始吧
- Ready? - Begin.
我是应届毕业生 主修地缘政治学 辅修文学专业
Graduated this year. Majored in geopolitics. Minor in tech studies.
兴趣在于政府与科技
Very interested in governmentand technology,
之间的对接应用
how that's gonna intersect and co-exist.
要塑造未来
Shape the future.
当初干嘛要费劲地送他去读常春藤盟校?
Why did we bother sending him to an lvy college for?
毕业三个月了 还找不到工作
Three months out of school and he can't find a job?
松笨先生
Mr. Masuhisu...
- 我叫松本 - 松...
- Matsumoto. - Atsu.
是“松本”
Matsumoto.
摩托
Moto.
- 玛莎 可以叫你玛莎吗? - 不 不可以
- Martha, can I call you Martha? - No, you may not.
好了 杰克 这世上有两种人
Okay, Jack, there's two types of people in this world.
一种是思想家 一种是实干家
There's think ers, there's doers.
一种是胜利者 一种是梦想者 还有一种是好哥们
There's winners, there's dreamers, and there's buddies.
跟我谈谈 你的缺点吧
What about some weaknesses?
哪里有啊
I don't...
您长得很亲切
You have a very trustworthy face.
就像是...亚洲版的肯德基爷爷
You remind me of like an Asian Colonel Sanders.
很值得我信任
A man I can trust.
他是80年后
He's a millennial.
你知道 他们是迷惘的一代
That means they're the, you know, like lost generation.
联邦调查局为什么找你?
Why was the FBI looking for you?
什么?
The what?
对 联邦调查局那事 是因为外星人闹事
Yeah, FBI. Good of you to flag that.
你十四岁时就没干过什么疯狂的事吗?
It was during all that alien craziness when you were 14.
他们对我很和气 很快就找到我
I mean, they were very kind to me, found me in a jiffy.
档案里也没有记录
And that's all been expunged.
但其实奥巴马给我发了奖章
Obama gave me a medal, actually.
我的意思是 不管怎样 招一个戴勋章的人
I'm just saying. It's always good to have a medal guy.
总不是坏事吧
in the office, with a medal.
- 奥巴马颁发的? - 对
- From Obama? - Yeah.
这个公司里 大多数人都支持共和党
In this office, we're mostly Republicans,
所以...
so...
- 我有点不舒服 - 是吗?
- I'm not feeling too good. - No?
- 嗯 - 干嘛不找个狗食盆?
- No. - Why don't you get a little dipping tray.
弄点拉肚子药 肯定能管用的
and dip the dog in Pepto? That's a solution.
糟了 还有一场 我们得闪了 快点
Pow, I got another one. We got to go. Come on.
不是吧
Really?
坐
Sit.
希望这次面试顺利
Got a nice sell from this.
山姆-维特维奇先生 应届大学毕业生
Mr. Sam Witwicky, recent college graduate.
之前工作经验几乎为零 但是...
Previous experience, next to zero, yet...
他却有本公司董事会的推荐信
he has a recommend letterfrom our board?
这是怎么回事
W.T.F to that.
我认识你们公司董事吗?
Do I know somebody on your board?
这么说吧 你也很了解
Here's the deal. You know who we are.
我们埃克塔系统公司是航天电信业的龙头企业
Accuretta Systems, global leader in telecom, aerospace,
去年盈利170亿
17 billion in profit last year.
国防部 航天局 实验室等等 都是我们的客户
We contract for DARPA, NASA, JPL, you name it.
你表现得好 你的发展前途就非常广阔
You perform here, doors open for you anywhere.
毕业后的第一份工作很重要 孩子
First job out of college is critical, kid.
你要是没有走上正确的职业道路
You either take a step down the correct career path.
后半辈子就掉到沟里去了
or you fall into a life-sucking abyss.
嗯
Hmm.
所以 一切都取决于你如何回答下面我唯一的要求
So, it all depends on how you respond to my next two words.
要能打动我
Impress me.
现在?
Now?
打动我
Impress me.
这我哪里有准备 从何说起呢?
You catch me off guard. I don't know where to begin.
打动我
Impress me.
我没有保留 随便您怎么问
I'm an open book. ask me any question you like.
那你就是很有野心 很强势
So you're a go get a ramrod...
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
是个控制狂?
...take-charge kind of guy?
我是个杀手 而且是冷血杀手
I'm a killer. A stone-cold killer.
那在控制欲方面
So, take-charge guy?
掌控一切 野蛮凶狠 我人就这样
Take-charge, Viking, barbarian, of course, that's me.
您看着办吧
Pow! I'm here.
我们要的不是这种人
We are not looking for that here.
我们不要马屁精 不要小人
No brown-nosing. No suck up.
不要仆人 我...
No toolery. I...
您好 布拉索斯先生
Yes, Mr. Brazos.
为什么尚塔尔会拿着...
Why is Shontel using.
...红色楼层才能用的红色杯子呢?
what appears to be a red cup from the red floor.
- 我们这层的主题是黄色 - 马上查
- when we are on the yellow floor? - I'm on it.
这是赤裸裸的视觉和灵魂上的背叛
It is a visual and, therefore, a visceral betrayal.
解决它
Stop it!
真是个白痴
Such a dumbass.
真恶心
Disgusting!
谢谢
Thank you!
这里简直是无法无天
It's total anarchy around here.
你们电子邮件里说是招收行政人员
The... e-mail I read said administrative aide?
不 是收发员
Nope. Mailroom.
我还是走吧
I'm going to go.
你知道有多少常春藤名校毕业生到我们这里...
Do you have any idea how many lvy League Phi Beta Kappas.
- 想来碰运气 - 先生 我曾经救过你的命两次了 好吗?
- would kill to... - Mister, I saved your life twice. Okay?
可是我不能告诉你时间 地点
I can't tell you how or when or why,
或是经过 但我真的做过大事
but I have done shit that matters.
而且我只是想再做点实事而已
and I'd just kind of like a job where I matter again.
所以谢了 不管怎么样 谢谢你
So thank you, but no, thank you, okay?
你知道我怎么想的吗?
You know what I think?
你得先干这个 才能干其它的
You want the job after this job.
你眼下只有这份差事可以做
But, son, this is the job that's standing in your way.
所以你一定会干得特别棒
And that's why you're gonna be so very, very good at it.
因为当我第一眼看到你时
'Cause when I look at you,
我就想起了年轻气盛时的自己
I see a younger me.
(华盛顿特区 NEST秘密总部)
(公共健康与社会福利部)
所有在勤汽车人报到 十五分钟后开始训练
All arriving Autobots, in par, training and debriefing in 15 minutes.
恐龙到23号车位报到
Dino, report to Bay 23.
横炮到37号车位进行武器评估
Sideswipe, Bay 37 for weapons assessment.
议员先生 您兴许知道 国家航空航天局
Senator, I suggest you remember that.
需要资金时会找我
when the NSA wants funding, they call me.
中情局若想消灭某个目标
When the CIA is gonna take out a target,
也得先获得我的许可
they ask first for my permission.
总统想了解
And when the President wants to know.
哪个国会参议员的政治把柄
which members of Congress are politically vulnerable.
比方说 某些不为人知的罪行
in terms of, let's say, undiscovered criminal conduct,
也会打电话问我
I'm the number he dials.
美国政府声称正在调查这宗爆炸案
U. S. Agencies say they have been monitoring the blast.
但事实上 这有可能是一次秘密的军事打击行动
But if, in fact, this was a covert military strike,
- 没有任何国家声称对此事件负责 - 中情局一再追问我
- no nation has claimed responsibility. - CIA is up my ass.
这次的幕后玄机
about this mystery raid in the Middle East.
所以你给我说清楚 这和你们有关吗?
So, it's time to come clean. Was your unit involved?
呃 我不能确定 女士
Uh. I'm not sure, ma'am.
好了 伙计们 这是在示范如何射击霸天虎的头部
All right, guys. This is how you do a Decepticon head kill shot.
我做为国家情报总监
As Director of National Intelligence,
希望你回答的时候动动脑子
I'm a really big fan of intelligent answers.
我真的没法确定
I can't really tell you definitively.
这些汽车人就像进入了青春期
These Autobots are like teenage kids.
动不动就跑出去玩
They like to sneak out of the house every once in a while.
伦诺克斯上校 你到底是不是这里的指挥官
Colonel Lennox, are you in command or are you not?
是的 女士 我是
Yes, ma'am, I am.
别叫我女士 我真是听够了
Stop with the "ma'am". Enough with the "ma'am".
我看起来有这么老吗?
Do I look like a "ma'am"?
是 女士 呃不 女士 只是像
No, ma'am. Yes, ma'am. Yes.
- 这枪可是我的完美杰作 铁皮 - 不错
- This gunis my perfect invention, Ironhide. - Right.
哦 他们来了 太好了
Good, you're here!
我叫Q 真的希望你们能对他有所交代
Me name's Que. I do hope you have answers for him.
我从没见过他如此火冒三丈
I've never seen him so upset.
擎天柱 还记得夏洛特·梅琳吗?
Optimus, you remember Charlotte Mearing?
我们的国家情报总监
Our Director of National Intelligence?
他情绪不太好
He's in a bad mood.
今天不想和任何人说话
He's not talking to anybody today.
这算什么意思?
What is this,
无声的抗议吗?
the silent treatment?
- 那个我们知道 - 这跟那不是一码事
- We've seen that and this is not that. - Definitely not.
比那还严重
This is worse.
擎天柱 你总得有所表示吧
Prime! Make something of yourself!
他都气疯了
He's pissed.
你骗了我们
You lied to us.
你们说过 一切有关我们星球的情报都会告诉我们
Everything humans know of our planet we were told had all been shared.
那这东西为什么会在人类的手里?
So why was this found in human possession?
我们起初也蒙在鼓里
We were in the dark on this also.
这事目前在第7区也只有局长知情
It was Director Only clearance at Sector 7 until now.
我的皮包
The bag.
哪个皮包?
Which bag?
爱马仕铂金包 绿色鸵鸟皮的那个
Herm. Birkin. Green ostrich!
哦 我的天
Oh, my God.
这个秘密只有极少数人知道
This is a secret few men knew,
目前在世的更是没几个
and fewer still remain alive.
容我向你介绍一下
Allow me to please introduce to you.
两位国家航空航天局的行动组要员
two of NASA's founding mission directors.
以及宇航员巴兹·奥尔德林博士
and astronaut Dr. Buzz Aldrin,
他是当年首次登月的两位人类先驱之一
one of the first two men to step foot on the moon.
您好
Sir.
这位是擎天柱
Optimus Prime.
你我都曾遨游太空 很荣幸见到你
From a fellow space traveler, it's a true honor.
见到您我也很荣幸
The honor is mine.
我们在60年代的整个太空军备竞赛
Our entire space race of the 1960s, it appears,
全都是针对一件事
was in response to an event.
我们的宇航员调查了一艘坠毁的外星飞船
Our astronauts investigated a crashed alien ship.
但并未发现幸存者
No survivors onboard.
上头要求我们严守秘密
We were sworn to secrecy by our Commander in Chief.
这项任务绝不能对任何人透露
This was a mission you will never speak of.
明白 长官
I understand, sir.
在国家航空航天局 也只有35个人知道这计划的真相
A total of 35 people knew the real plan at NASA.
苏联成功发射了无人登月探测器
Soviets managed to land unmanned probes.
他们大概是在那时取走了那根燃料棒
Somehow they must have picked up that fuel rod.
我们相信苏联人发现
We believe the Russians deduced.
那燃料棒可以进行核裂变反应
that the rod was a fissionable fuel assembly,
并在切尔诺贝利核电站对其进行实验
believed they had it mastered, and tried to harness it at Chernobyl.
我们共组织了6次登月行动
We landed six missions in all.
拍下了数百幅照片 采集了样本
We took hundreds of photos and samples.
并将其永久封存
We locked them away forever,
之后探月计划便终止了
and the moon program was shut down.
你们搜查过防撞逃生舱吗?
Well, did you search the crash vault?
那艘飞船名叫“方舟”
The ship's name was the Ark.
我曾亲眼看着它逃离塞伯坦
I watched it escape Cybertron myself.
船上携带了一项汽车人的核心科技
It was carrying an Autobot technology.
本可以帮助我们赢得战争
which would have won us the war.
还有那艘船的船长
And its captain.
- 船长是谁? - 伟大的御天敌
- Who was its captain? - The great Sentinel Prime,
那项技术的发明者
the technology's inventor.
他也是汽车人的超级领袖
He was commander of the Autobots.
我的前任
before me.
我必须找到方舟
It's imperative that I find it.
抢在霸天虎之前
before the Decepticons learn of its location.
我们汽车人的宇宙飞船有能力飞往月球
Our Autobot spacecraft has the ability to get there.
所以 你们必须祈祷这还来得及
And you must pray it's in time.
嗨 我找卡莉·斯宾塞
Hi. I'm here to see Carly Spencer.
卡莉
Carly!
你找到工作了?
You got the job?
- 简直不可思议 - 你真的找到了?
- This is crazy. - You really got it?
- 是的 - 看 我怎么说的来的? 兔子给你好运气
- Yes. - See, what did I tell you? It's the bunny.
你太受欢迎了
You are so welcome.
- 是不是更爱我了? - 好感度上升了点
- Do you like me more? - A little bit, yeah.
你只说你管这博物馆
You said you were his assistant curator,
没说你有这么个宝贝啊
you didn't say the guy owns Space Mountain.
是吧 这里很漂亮吧
I know. Isn't it beautiful in here?
而且 我老板也是个超酷的家伙
And he's the coolest guy. Ever.
- 是吗? - 是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
山姆
Sam.
迪伦·古尔德
Dylan Gould.
嘿
Hey.
幸会
A pleasure to meet you.
Pleasure meeting you.
卡莉经常提起你
Carly's told me a lot about you.
呃 她也常跟我提起您 这里真的挺漂亮
Well, vice versa. It's a beautiful building you got.
像《星际迷航》里的布景
It's like the Starship Enterprise in here.
过奖 这里也漏雨
Thank you very much. It leaks.
在卡莉来帮忙打理之前
Before Carly came to help run the collection,
这整个场馆还是一团糟呢
it was just a complete mess.
但是现在装修工作总算重回正轨了
But now, the restorations are back on track.
我们要去圆石滩巡展
We're going to Pebble Beach this year,
再赢一座奖杯回来 放在这里
and we're gonna get a trophy for that stand right there.
你知道为什么吗?
You know why?
因为眼前这位小美女
Because this woman right here.
就是我的秘密武器
is my secret weapon.
- 好吧 - 古尔德先生 别这样 您过奖了
- Okay. - Mr. Gould, please, you exaggerate.
我只是负责组织工作
All I've done is get you organized.
哦 你的功劳可多得多呢 我的公爵夫人
You've done much more than that, my Duchess.
用昵称 有意思
Nicknames, that's fun.
没错 公爵夫人
Yeah. The Duchess.
她人见人爱
She's adorable.
我把她从英国大使馆挖过来时
You know, when I stole her away from the British Embassy,
对她说 治国有何难?
I said, "It's easy to manage a country".
还不如来管理无价的艺术收藏品
"Try managing a priceless collection of art".
看看这辆1939年出厂的德拉哈耶-165型敞篷跑车
Take a lookat this 1939 Delahaye 165 Cabriolet.
法国人设计的
Designed by a Frenchman.
瞧瞧她的曲线 如此优雅 不是吗?
Look at the curves. Elegant, isn't it?
美丽
Beautiful.
性感
Sensual.
如同窈窕淑女的曲线
Built to evoke the body of the ideal woman.
跟我来
Come on.
我父亲只靠一张破烂书桌和一个梦想
My dad had a $ 10 desk and a dream,
就建立了一个商业帝国
and he built it into an empire.
- 吼吼 哇哦 - 我们现在是全美最大的会计事务所
- Hoho Wow. - We're the largest accounting firm in the U. S.
他去世之后我从创投部门开始
I started up the venture side after he passed.
投资未来
Invest in the future.
试着把赌注压到获胜者的那一方
Try and bet on the winners.
而收集名车能帮助我在赌局中保持理智
See, collecting cars helps me keep my sanity.
看起来不错
You guys look great.
哦 那天确实不错 古尔德先生
Oh. That was a great day, Mr. Gould.
- 我没见过这张 - 我也没看过呢
- I haven't seen that one. - No. Me, neither.
牛仔裤太紧了
Jeans are tight.
哦 又来了 又是这套
Oh. Here we go. Here we go.
你都看见了
You see that?
又以车取人了
Judgment. Judging a man by his car?
他以车取人的时候 你居然无动于衷?
And you're gonna wave at him while he's judging me?
你怎么啦? 他是我老板呐
What's with you? He's my boss.
我们吃的住的花得都是他的钱
He still pays for our food, our rent.
不是 我完全理解
No, I totally understand .
我是无所谓 我饿不着
I'm totally fine, I get it. I'm well fed.
知道吗?
And guess what?
我不用你供养了 我也穿正装了
I'm not your boy toy anymore. I got my big boy pants on.
看见没?
You see them?
请上车 谢谢 公爵夫人
In the car. Thank you, Duchess.
哦 天啊 他对你构成威胁了吗?
Oh, my God. Are you threatened by him?
威胁? 我怕他什么?
Threatened? What am I threatened by?
怕他有钱 有权 长得帅?
His money? His power? His good looks?
全都是浮云 记好了
None of the above. Check!
你吃醋的样子还真性感
God! Your temper tantrums are so sexy.
上车吧 拜托了
Get in the car, please.
山姆 他又不是第一个对我笑的男人
Sam, he's hardly the first man to ever smile at me.
我自有分寸
I think I can handle it.
等等 等等
Hold on, hold on.
可你也冲他笑了 别说你没笑 好吗?
It's, It's the smiling back part that gets me. Okay?
那我不笑了 以后不朝他笑了 我发誓
No more smiles Never again. I promise.
- 这话我爱听 - 好吧
- That works for me. - yeah.
别急 别急
Easy! Easy!
那样可发动不了
You're not gonna get it started that way.
我是在做准备
Well, I was just getting it ready.
我只完成了32%的修复
I'm about 32% done with my restoration.
一些镀铬零件 加上扰流板就搞定了
Some chrome work, put a spoiler on the back. Done deal.
卡莉一直跟我说 你找工作很辛苦
You know, Carly's been telling me you've been struggling job-wise.
所以让你知道
Just so you know,
我也是埃克塔系统公司的董事
I'm on the board for Accuretta Systems,
我跟他们打了个招呼
and I put in a call for you.
这事就我们俩知道就行了 好吗?
Let's keep it between us, okay?
她对你太好了
She's so proud of you.
你真是个幸运儿
You're a lucky man.
苍耳号 接近月球静海基地
Xanthium approaching Tranquility Base.
这里是休斯顿 苍耳号 准备降落
Here's Houston, you're a go Xanthium. You're a go for landing.
阿姆斯特朗 祝你顺利
Armstrong, having a good day.
铁皮 我们走
Ratchet, let's roll.
他们会说...
They gonna say...
35亿美元...
Three half Billion...
他们把传感器打开了吗?
Did they get that mag cap on?
收到 保持联系
Roger Copy contact.
我们正在进入方舟号
We're entering the Ark.
他的生命指数很微弱
His levels are faint.
他把自己锁起来
He locked himself away.
以保护那些能量柱
to guard the pillars.
御天敌
Sentinel.
欢迎你回家 老朋友
You're coming home, old friend.
威震天万岁
All hail Megatron.
是主人 主人回来了
My master! Yes, my master! Yes!
啊 别这么贪吃
Ah, Don't be greedy,
我脆弱的小宝贝们
my fragile ones.
您气色很不好 主人
My poor master.
看到您如此虚弱 真是让我...
How it pains me to see you so wounded, so weak.
心痛不已 少来那套奉承话
Spare me, you gaseous sycophant!
之前怎么教训你的来的? 少说废话
You know what you are told, which is nothing.
威震天陛下 震荡波向您报告
Soundwave reporting, Lord Megatron.
你的小刺客带来了什么新消息?
And what news from your little assassin?
汽车人上钩了
Autobots have taken the bait!
他们找到了方舟 带走了上面的东西
They've discovered the Ark and returned with its cargo.
你跟踪那飞船一直到月球 干得漂亮
You did me great honortracking that ship to the moon.
你的人类合作伙伴已经物尽其用 震荡波
Your human collaborators have served their purpose, Soundwave.
该让他们闭嘴了
It's time to eliminate loose ends.
激光鸟 杀光他们
Laserbeak, kill them all.
乐意之至
With pleasure.
你爸爸在家吗?
Is your daddy home?
- 接着亚当说该我们了 - 玛德琳
- "Then Adam said it's our time...." - Madeline!
你好 妈妈
Hello, Mom.
救命
help.
从我家滚出去
Get out of the house!
- 你来我家干什么? - 只是路过回访
- What are you doing in my house? - Just visiting.
你穿的这是爆乳装吗?
What is this hoochie-mama outfit?
姐穿什么关你屁事?
It's not your business about my wearing.
不行 我们公司做的是航空工业
No. This is the aerospace baby.
我们不允许这样
You are not allowed back here.
大不了老娘不干了
Damn it, I'm resign.
新来的 你看到了吗?
New guy! You see that?
崩溃的拉丁女人就是这样
That's a Latin meltdown, okay?
在我办公室里 你要是穿着不得体 就会被炒鱿鱼
You ever show up in my office with a hoochie-mama outfit, you're fired.
明白了吗?好吗?
You got that? Okay.
这小车会跟你待上两年半
you're gonna be on this cart for two-and-a-half years, okay?
你吃喝拉撒都得带着它
I want you to live it, love it and name it.
在我这里没有捷径可走 我要求很严 明白吗?
There's no ladder climbing in my office. I run a tight ship. Okay?
- 是 先生 - 开始工作
- Yes, sir. - Move!
上次提到的那份报告 我找到了
I found that paper I was telling you about.
你在看什么?
What are we looking at?
闭嘴
Shut up!
再对我这样 我就揍你
You do that to me again, and I'll kick your ass!
嗨 宝贝
Hi, angel.
你好吗?
How are you?
不错
Good.
我到市中心开会 顺便来看看你 不妨碍吧?
I had a meeting downtown. Was it okay for me to stop by?
没想到这本500页的员工行为手册
I don't know. My 500-page employee conduct manual.
是如此乏味
isn't exactly a page turner.
看起来很沉闷
This is great.
汽车人在四处拯救世界 而我却在整理这些信件
Yeah, Autobots are off saving the world, and I have organized four binders.
瞧这工作多理想 跟我来
I'm living the dream. Come on.
外人不许随便进出
Visitor violation.
你还好吗?
You okay?
当然
Absolutely.
我在排队
I'm next.
听好 这星期六
Listen. Saturday.
迪伦要在他家里搞聚会
Dylan's throwing a party at his house.
虽然是项工作但他也邀请了你
It's a work thing, but he's invited you, too.
是吗? 他请了?
Did he?
到时可别吐槽我的冷笑话
I want you to come and laugh at my bad jokes.
这对我很重要 知道吗?
It would really mean a lot to me, okay?
那我去 你怎么来这儿的?
I'd love to go. How'd you get over here?
开车
Car.
你明明没有车
You don't have a car.
现在有了
Yes, I do.
你中大奖了?
What, did you win it in a raffle?
他给了我一辆
He gave me one.
他给了你一辆车?
He gave you a car?
嗯 就算是员工福利吧
Yeah, I think it was a work perk.
呵 员工福利
Hmm, a work perk.
他给了你辆什么车?
What kind of car did he give you?
- 一辆梅赛德斯SLS-AMG - 嗯
- Um, a Mercedes SLS AMG. - Hmm.
引擎声音很低沉
Really throaty engine.
梅赛德斯 奔驰 SLS-AMG
Mercedes-Benz SLS combines breathtaking...
你开着它来的?
You drove this here?
这车价值20万美元
That's a $200, 000 car.
我知道
I know.
你知道我得赚多久钱才能买得起这车吗?
You know how long it would take me to afford a car like this?
- 很久 - 嗯 大约53年
- A long time? - Yeah, like 53 years.
他说了这算是员工福利了
He said it was for both of us.
知道我们该怎么做吗? 应该卖了它买房子
Then what we should do is, we should sell it and buy a house.
你很沮丧 我知道
You're frustrated, I know.
我也经历过
I've been there.
这就叫做先苦后甜
It's called paying your dues.
好日子总会来的
Good things will happen.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我需要有人牺牲午饭时间来做文件归档
I need some lunch time filing done, stat.
谁愿意让布鲁斯·布拉索斯多加点印象分?
Who would like to score some Bruce Brazos points?
布鲁斯 你找到人了
Bruce, you found your guy.
维特维奇
Witwicky!
本公司的栋梁之才
The man who makes this company run.
这位是谁啊? 妹妹? 脸谱网友?
Now, who have we here? Is it a sister, Facebook friend,
推特粉丝?
Twitter tweeter?
- 卡莉 这是布鲁斯 布鲁斯 - 嗨
- Carly, this is Bruce. Bruce. - Hi.
我是他的女友 幸会
I'm his girlfriend. A pleasure to meet you.
山姆说得没错 您的发型真的很帅
Sam was right. You really do have a smashing head of hair.
- 嗯 谢谢你 - 不客气
- Well, thank you. - Your welcome.
- 山姆 我得走了 - 好吧
- Sam, I got to run. - Yeah.
给你 送你的礼物
Here, your present.
是你最喜欢的颜色
Your favorite color.
见到您很高兴 布拉索斯先生
Nice to meet you, Mr. Brazos.
我也是
And you.
小伙子们 再见
See you, boys.
活页夹的事搞得我很不爽 杰瑞
I'm still stewing about that binder incident, Jerry.
等我喝完舒化奶再说 唐尼
May I finish my Shuhua milk, Donny?
我才不在乎你的外国牛奶
I don't care about your exotic milk.
我说的是尊重
I care about respect!
我知道你是谁
I know who you are!
维特维奇 维特维奇
Witwicky! Witwicky!
- 知道吗? 我在和你说话 - 借过
- You know who I'm talking to you! - Excuse me...
谢谢你
Thank you.
喔喔喔 慢一点 小老虎
Wow, wow, wow, slow down, tiger.
你在六张不同照片的背景里出现
You showed up in the backgroundof six different photos,
和外星人一起去过两个大陆
two continents, with aliens.
而且那个在埃及的人就是你
That was you in Egypt,
嗯 对吧?
Uh, right?
因为你认识那些外星人
Because you know the aliens.
回头见
See you!
还我外套
Give me my jacket!
嘿 我姓王 王深
Hi, I'm Wang. Deep Wang.
王深
Deep Wang.
你不明白吗? “深喉”探员
You're not getting it. Deep Throat.
水门事件?我在跟你说暗号
Watergate? I'm talking code to you...
该死的
Damn it.
他们在监视监听
They watch and listen.
我不能去找政府 但是你可以
I can't go to the government, but you can!
因为要出事了 孩子
Because shit's going down, son!
代号是“平克” 平克·佛洛伊德的“平克”
It is Code Pink, as in Floyd!
暗面 你知道为什么1972年后 就没人去那里了吗?
Dark Side! Why do you thinkno one's been up there since 1972?
你讲的是英语 但是却是听不懂的英语
I know you're speaking English, it's just a very strange English.
- 因此我... - 哦...哦
- That's why I'm not... - Oh... oh.
不要 我会打你的
Don't. I'm gonna hit you.
别打了 你会感谢我的
I'm gonna hit you right back, son.
这是我的声明书
It's my manifesto.
他们要干掉我们
They're whacking us out,
干掉每个知道暗面内情的人
everyone who knows what's on the dark...
你的外星朋友有难
Your alien friends is in danger.
你知道谁是好人 随你怎么处置
You know the good ones, it's up to you.
下来
Calm down.
放松 山姆
Easy, Sam!
你看什么看?
What are you looking at?
哼 你这老狗
Yo, dawg.
看我的屎吗?
Are you up in my shit?
你为谁工作?
Who are you working for?
看谁能瞪过谁
Staredown, you and me.
看来我赢了
Guess I won.
月球清单
Moon satellites.
更多被搁置的计划
The Russian space program.
专家身亡
Experts dead.
太空计划结束
Space program ends.
暗面
Dark side...
月之暗面
Dark side of the moon.
看看我在洗手间找到了什么
Look what I found outside the bathroom.
是你的吗? 去处理好这些东西
Is it yours? Deal with this.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
你让我做的事情我都做了
I did everything you want!
我想我们该好好谈谈 因为有些事情...
I really think we should talk, 'cause some of the stuff...
哇 要先敲门
Whoa! Knock first!
没看到我正忙着吗?
Can't you see I'm busy?
你是谁 你是谁?
Who are you? Who are you?
你刚才在隔间里跨在我身上
You straddled me in the stall.
我这辈子头回遇上这种事 我忘不了的
That's happened to me once in this life. I wouldn't forget it.
在厕所的隔间里
From the bathroom stall.
你把你的东西掏了出来
You took your package out.
哇噢...我们不是同性恋 好吗?
Whoa! Whoa! We are not boyfriends, okay?
我打个电话就可以把你炒掉
One phone call from meand I'll have you fired.
哦 没错 我会的 同性恋
Oh, yes I will, Gaylord.
你还好吧?
Are you okay?
痔疮犯了
Hemorrhoids!
我该回来吗? 我该什么时候再过来?
Should I come back? When should I come back?
等你学会礼貌再来
Come back when you learn some manners!
我不认识他 我什么都没说
I don't know him! I would never say anything!
好吧好吧
Okay, okay!
事实会证明的 就像我承诺过的
I sabotaged the mapping satellite, just like I promised,
我会守口如瓶
I can put a blind spot in the program as a bonus.
你还要我干些什么?
What more do you want from me?
杰瑞
Jerry,
你是我的最爱
you are my favorite.
你让我干什么都行
I'll do whatever you want me to do.
我知道
I know,
我的主人要求我...
but my superiors need me to...
- 拜托 你没必要... - ...杀了你
- Please, you don't have to... - ...suicide you.
你对维特维奇说了些什么?
What did you say to Witwicky?
啊哈 你妹的
Ah hah... Shit!
啊?想尝尝鸡肉大餐吗? 贱货
Huh? Who wants some chick en dinner now, bitch?
今天真的有人把我姓王的惹毛了
'Cause somebody messed with the wrong Wang today!
来吧 你想要杀我吗?
Come on! You want some of me?
不...不...不
No no no no...
我不想再听到查克没完没了的唠叨
I don't need any more didactic lectures from Chuck.
天啊
Jesus!
通知法律部
Get legal.
那是杰瑞
That's Jerry!
大家注意 没错 有同事死了
Come on, people. Yes, a workmate died,
但是光看窗外是不会令他复活的
but looking out the window is not going to bring him back.
他得了抑郁症
The man was depressed.
别拍照
Don't take a picture!
你们可以一直看 但他不会站起来
You can keep watching him, but he's not getting up.
“从墙上摔下蛋形胖矮子”
You all read "Humpty Dumpty".
好了
Okay.
维特维奇
Witwicky.
我去对付媒体 你来打扫现场
I'm spearheading the press. You clean up.
老王摔的到处都是
Wang is everywhere.
酒吧里有 树林里有 栏杆上也有
He is in the bistro. He's in the bamboo. He's on the balustrade.
看到下面的人行道了吗?
You see the sidewalk down there? Man!
天哪
Man!
帮他打包 去掉他停车位上的名字
Box up his personals. Get his name off his parking space.
嘿 我们什么时候又买了一台影印机?
Hey, when did we get a new copier?
听着 刚才看到的事情 我会保密
Listen, I'm not gonna say anything about what I saw.
你和谁共用一间厕所完全是你个人的事
Who you share a toilet stall with is totally your business.
这一定是日货
This is exceedingly Japanese.
日货用起来一向不好操作
They never make it easy, do they?
你怎么了?
What is with you?
出大事了 卡莉
This is the real deal, Carly, okay?
好吧 我需要你保持冷静
I need you to stay composed.
这是真事 我等一下会给你解释
It's real life. I'll explain it to you later.
我们遇到了紧急情况 快把伦诺克斯上校找来
We've got an emergency. You gotta get Colonel Lennox out here.
我指的是霸天虎 霸天虎又杀回来了
I'm reporting a Decepticon. The Decepticons are back.
- 你们得立即开门 - 冷静点 先生
- You gotta open that gate right now. - Easy, sir.
这里是公共健康与社会福利部
This is Health and Human Services.
是啊 还拿着M-4步枪?
Right. Packing M4s?
你们保护什么 尿袋?
What are you protecting, colostomy bags?
- 便盆? 止咳糖浆? - 亲爱的...
- Bedpans? Throat lozenges? - Babe...
你们的帽子从哪里来的? 护理学校?
Where'd you get that hat from, nursing school?
难道说你们是在保卫护士和脚气药粉?
So, you're nurses and foot-powder protectors?
- 妙极了... - 是的 - 宝贝 我们是不是...
- Oh, fantastic... - Yes. - Baby, I don't think we're in...
我们没走错
We're in the right place.
我们找对门了
We are in the right place.
我们找的就是这里 我要和擎天柱讲话
We're in the right place and I'm gonna talk to Optimus right now.
- 先生 - 马上带我去见擎天柱
- Sir. - You're gonna get Optimus out here.
我想你来错地方了
you got the wrong building.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
霸天虎杀回来了 你们哪句话没听懂?
What part of "Decepticons are back"do you not understand?
你
You!
最好放明白点
You being a smartass?
别碰我的车 这可是古董
Do not hit my car! It's a collector's item!
我不会这么做
I wouldn't do that.
你疯了
You're crazy!
发现了外星能量讯号
We got an Energon reading!
讯号来自车内
We've got aliens in the vehicle!
不许动
You move, you're dead!
出来 出来
Out! Out! Out!
关闭引擎
Got aliens in the vehicle!
不许动
Freeze!
- 喔喔喔 我们不动 - 出来
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, we're freezing. - Get out!
你们...
Are you...
你们在开玩笑吗?
Are you kidding me?
住手 住手
Sam, they've got guns!
- 我抓住他了 - 大黄蜂
- I got him. Go! - Bee!
大黄蜂 你在吗?
Is Bee in there?
好了 好吧
Okay, all right!
你们就是这样对待汽车人吗?
This how you treat Autobots?
都是自己人
We're on the same team.
祝你将来在7-11便利店打工愉快 白痴
Yeah, enjoy your next job at 7-11, dickhead.
- 说得没错 - 浑球
- That's right. - A-hole.
你的车呢?
How's your car now?
那才是我的车
That's my car.
过来
Come here.
Come here!
说吧 山姆
Come on. Sam.
你怎么回事?
What is your deal?
我知道你们的秘密行动很重要
I know your black ops stuff is important to you.
我并没有轻视 也不想让你内疚
I'm not trying to diminish it or guilt-trip you or anything,
可我再也没见过你的面
I just never see you anymore.
你就不能回车库待一晚上吗?
You can't come to the garage and just hang out one night?
山姆 这话让我好难过
Sam. That makes me feel bad.
是的 我希望你感到难过 你应该感到难过
I hope you feel bad. You should feel bad.
看看我现在开的这辆破车
Look at the jalopy I'm driving now.
我每天都感到难过
I feel bad every single day.
喂 你们两个都过来
Yo, let's go, both of you.
伦诺克斯要见你们
Lennox wants to see you.
怎么? 你们不再扣留我们了?
What, we not good enough for you anymore?
对不起 他们过于粗暴了
I'm sorry, babe. They were very rude, all right?
你得给我去修车
And you're fixing my car.
你以为会没事?
You don't think so?
还要举手检测
Raise your hand.
要是你今天被疯狂的飞行杀手影印机追杀
if you hada flying psycho-ninja copier trying to kill you today!
这是我的黄铜拳釦
Those are my brass knuckles.
那是我的脚环 需要我脱掉吗?
That's my anklet. Do I have to take that off, too?
脚趾环呢?
And my toe rings?
本层展物全部撤走
All NEST officials clear the floor.
距离接触行动 还有10分钟
We have 10 minutes until attempted contact.
我们获得了五件仪器
We've taken possession of the five devices.
藏在御天敌飞船里的
that were hidden in the shipwith Sentinel Prime.
它们都是某种汽车人科技的原型机
They're some kind of prototype Autobot technology.
他们说 御天敌相当于汽车人的爱因斯坦
They say Sentinel was the Einstein of his civilization,
所以我们要锁好这些东西
so we're gonna keep these locked up.
尤其是在搞清它们的用处之前
until we know what we're dealing with.
现在任何人不得入内
Right now, no one gets access.
- 任何人 - 今天早上 有个姓王的家伙认出了我
- No one. - This Wang guy recognized me.
他让我来警告你们
He told me to warn you.
而且还提到了月之暗面
He was talking about the dark side of the moon,
- 然后他们杀了他 - 等一下 你说月球?
- then they killed him. - Wait a minute. He mentioned the moon?
是的 月之暗面
Yeah, dark side of the moon.
霸天虎为什么要暗杀人类?
But why would Decepticons want to kill humans?
我觉得他们的对手应该是汽车人
I thought their war was with the Autobots.
当时他做了一份报告
And that is when he made his first quick-look science report.
那是我想要的...
That's what we want...
这女孩是谁?
Who's the chick? Okay.
打扰了 伦诺克斯上校
Excuse me! Colonel Lennox?
梅琳主任
Director Mearing,
这位是山姆·维特维奇
this is Sam Witwicky...
- 一个平民... - 我认识他 上校
- A civilian c... - I know his name, Colonel.
我想知道谁给了他许可?
I wanna know who gave him clearance?
谁给了我许可? 擎天柱行不行
Who gave me clearance? How about Optimus Prime,
当时他跑到我们那里寻找我家
when he touched down in suburbia looking for my house?
这位是国家情报处主任
This is the National Intelligence Director.
如果你不知道的话...
In case you...
- 嗨 - 藐视联邦官员
- Hi. - Disrespecting a federal officer?
这就够你受的了 她是谁?
Maybe that'll get you somewhere. Who's she?
她是我女友
She's my girlfriend.
这算什么 约会吗?
What is this, like, a date?
汽车人的事她全知道
She knows all about the Autobots, okay?
她知道大黄蜂 她来自一个军人家庭
She knows Bumblebee. And she comes from a military family.
我可以为她担保
I can vouch for her.
好吧 我有主意了
Hey, I have an idea. How about.
我们还是谈谈正事吧?
we get back to the important topics,
比如 我今天差点就被一个霸天虎砍了头
like the fact that I almost had my face cut off by a Decepticon?
做为一名纳税人 我想我可以抗议
As a taxpayer, I'd like to lodge a complaint,
- 事实上... - 好吧
- as a matter of fact. - Okay,
听着
Lis. listen.
山姆办公室的一名软件工程师
One of the software engineers at Sam's office.
今天被暗杀了
was murdered today.
他参与过国家航空航天局的探月项目
He was involved in NASA's lunar mapping probe.
情况是这样 伦诺克斯上校
Here's the thing, Colonel Lennox.
我们不能把国家安全交付给这些年轻人
We cannot entrust national security to teenagers.
除非我违反政策文件
unless I missed a policy paper.
能让这种事发生吗?
Are we doing that now?
不能 很好
No. Good.
我不在乎你是谁
I don't care who you are.
如果你敢泄露你所看到的一切 那怕一个字
If you breathe a word of what you've seen here.
你将会因叛国罪而坐牢
You will do time for treason.
明白我的话吗?
Do you understand me?
我只听汽车人的命令
I'll take my orders from the Autobots.
我认识他们 我不认识你
I know them, I don't know you.
你会的
You will.
御天敌
Sentinel Prime.
他靠能量生存 但现在没能量了
These things run on Energon, and he's out of it.
他现在处于休眠状态
He's in asort of a sleep mode.
我们开始吧
Let us begin.
这就是伟大的领导矩阵
That's the great Matrix of Leadership.
他手里有宇宙中绝无仅有的东西
He holds the only thing in the universe.
只有它才能给变形金刚的火种补充能量
that can repower a Transformer's spark.
难以置信
This is incredible.
御天敌
Sentinel Prime,
请你醒来吧
we bid you return.
复仇
Revenge.
- 不 - 住手 别开火
- No. - Hold your fire.
不 御天敌
Stop! Sentinel!
别开火
Hold your fire.
是我 擎天柱
It is I, Optimus Prime!
一切都好
It is all right.
你很安全
You are safe.
没什么可害怕的
There is nothing to fear.
我们都在这里
We are here.
你到家了 御天敌
You are home, Sentinel.
战争呢 战争
The war... The war!
战争失败了
The war was lost.
塞伯坦成了一片废墟
Cybertron is now but a barren wasteland.
我们逃难到了地球
We have taken refuge here, on planet Earth.
这里的人类是我们的盟友
It's human race is our ally.
我的飞船呢?
My ship.
我们冲破战火而来
We came under fire.
能量柱
The pillars.
能量柱在哪里?
Where are the pillars?
你救出了5根
You saved five of them,
包括主控柱
including the control pillar.
只有5根?
Only five?
我们曾经有数百根
We once had hundreds!
对不起 先生们
Excuse me, gentlemen.
我可以问一下 你们在开发的是什么技术?
May I ask, what is this technology you're looking for?
它具有重塑宇宙的能力
It is the ability to reshape the universe.
能量柱结合在一起就可以形成太空桥
Together the pillars form a space bridge.
是我设计的 只有我一个人才能操作
I designed, and I alone, can control it.
它违背了你们的物理定律
It defies your laws of physics.
能够超时空传送物质
to transport matter through time and space.
你们说的是一种远程传送装置 对吧?
You're talking about a teleportation device, aren't you?
是的 可以传送资源 难民
Yes, for resources, for refugees.
难民或者士兵
Refugees, or troops of soldiers,
武器 甚至炸弹
weapons, maybe bombs!
一种瞬间袭击的手段
A means of an instant strike,
这就是它的军事用途 对吧?
that's its military function, isn't it?
这是我们的技术
It is our technology.
必须拿回来
and it must be returned.
对 得人类同意才行
Yes. If humans say so.
你们不能随便把大规模杀伤性武器
You can't just bring weapons of.
带入我们的大气层
mass destruction into our atmosphere!
至少要先申报海关
You kind of have to clear customs first!
还要走一些官方手续
A little formality called paperwork.
这就是我们和动物之间的区别
kind of separates us from the animals.
你如果能够充分尊重我
I will overlook your condescending tone.
我就原谅你的趾高气昂
if you heed the gravity of mine.
霸天虎不知道太空桥在这里
The Decepticons must never know the space bridge is here.
一旦入他们手中
For in their hands,
那就是你们的世界末日
it would mean the end of your world.
“头号威胁”文件
"Total Nightmare" file.
调查行动开始了
So, the investigation is open.
我们会派探员去你的办公室
We've sent agents to your office.
现在 我们打算
And, for the time being,
派汽车人护送你们回家
we're gonna send you home with Autobot protection.
我应该和谁谈
Who do I need to speak to.
才能让你们明白我能帮上忙?
to get you guys to understand that I can help,
我可以尽一份力
that I can contribute?
嘿 我们都能帮忙 告诉我你知道什么
Hey, we can all help. Want to tell you what I know?
我告诉你太阳系里
I could tell you about the solar system,
我去过的有趣星球
all the fun planets to hang out in.
拜托从我桌子上下去
Get off my desk, please.
喔 居然掏枪 算了 我不想帮你了
Aw, you pulling out guns. Okay, can't help you on that.
天哪
Oh, my god.
你们想要我干什么? 让我回家去工作
What do you envision for me? I go home now?
让我回去玩影印机是吗? 我是说.
I go back to work? I make copies? I mean...
这个组织的成员都是些老探员和特种部队
This is a unit for veteran intelligence officers and Special Forces,
可不是有特殊汽车的男孩来的地方
not for boys who once owned special cars.
你有点刻薄了吧 女士?
That's a bit harsh, isn't it, ma'am?
不要叫我女士 我不是女士
Don't call me ma'am. I'm not a ma'am.
你不是女的吗?
Well, you're a woman, aren't you?
那么...
So,
这些是你的?
are those yours?
是的 中情局发的
Yeah. CIA.
我之所以问是因为我也有奖章
I only ask 'cause I also have a medal,
总统发的
from the President.
没错 很好
Yeah. Great.
好 那我就不兜圈子明说吧
So, it's not that complicated, right?
没有我同意 谁都不能和汽车人合作
No one gets to work with the Autobots unless I approve it.
你破坏了我的指挥程序
You're breaking my chain of command.
好吧 我们走
Come on, let's go.
你能做的都做了
You've done what you came for.
老实说 小伙子
With all due respect, young man,
我感谢你做的一切
I appreciate what you did.
但你不是军人
But you're not a soldier.
你只是个送信的 永远都是
You're a messenger. You've always been a messenger.
他是个英雄
He's a hero.
大黄蜂 你去坐货运电梯 我们楼上见
Bee, you take the freight elevator. I'll see you up there.
啊 真是鬼扯
Ah, this blows.
- 那个女人把我们踢出来了 - 没错
- That lady officially kicked us out. - Yeah.
证人保护程序烂透了
Witness Protection Program sucks.
说得不错 但有大黄蜂在至少我们更安全了
Yeah, but we're a whole lot safer with big yellow and his cannons.
那条狗可保护不了咱们
That dog can't protect crap.
大黄蜂
Bee?
你想出去?
You miss hanging out?
是啊 我也想
Yeah, me, too.
那个女人 她说我是个送信的
That woman, she called me a messenger.
你们能相信吗?
Can you believe that?
忙了半天 我只是个送信的
After everything I've done, I'm a messenger.
哦 我相信你山姆 说实话我们也有同感
Oh, I believe it. I tell ya, Sammy, we feel the same way.
这个星球上的人都不懂得尊重别人
The disrespect on this rock is criminal.
我们应该做点什么
We should do something about it.
大黄蜂
Bee,
我要知道他们为什么追杀人类
I need to know why they're killing humans.
咱们得找个专家问问
I say we call in the expert.
下一位嘉宾是前美国情报人员
My next guest is a former American intelligence operative.
他曾为我们爆出猛料
who has dared to speak out.
揭露了我们国家
regarding our alleged military alliance with what many describe.
和所谓的外星僱佣兵之间的军事同盟
as a groupof extraterrestrial mercenaries.
他就是畅销书《代号-英雄》的作者
He is the author of the bestselling book, Code-Name Hero.
有请前探员西摩·西蒙斯
Former special agent, Seymour Simmons.
比尔 粉丝们 很高兴接受专访
Bill. Big fan. Great to be here.
西蒙斯探员 你想让我们相信
Now, Agent Simmons, you would have us believe.
对我们来说最要紧的事情
that it is in our best interest.
就是在这场外星人内战中选好阵营 是吗?
to formally take sidesin this so-called alien civil war?
其中一派想把我们剁了做早餐吃
Well, the other side wanted to spank us for breakfast,
所以 我们其实没什么选择余地
so I wouldn't exactly call it a toss-up.
那些霸天虎相当凶残
These Decepticons are lethal.
但民调显示 世界上一半的人都认为会更加安全
But polls show half the world would feel safer.
让汽车人离开地球
with the Autobots completely gone.
让他们滚出去
Get them out of here!
我们不需要他们
We don't need them here!
那为了安全 我只能抱着手榴弹睡觉了
I feel safer when I sleep with a hand grenade.
我这话未必对
Doesn't mean I'm always right.
探员先生 事实上我们得到了关于你的资料
Now, agent, here at The Factor we have obtained documents.
你是被情报委员会开除的
that show you were fired...
- 查斯 我在做访谈 - 抱歉 西蒙
- Chaz, I'm doing an interview. - Sorry, Mr. Simmons.
只是机构裁员 经费削减了...查斯 滚出去
Downsized, Bill. Budget cuts. Chaz, out.
这里是你的精神检验报告上面说 你有严重的妄想倾向
Your psych evaluation reports "severe delusional tendencies".
你这是搞突袭啊
This is ambush journalism.
你想了解外星人联盟的真相吗?
You want the truth about the alien alliance?
买我的书吧
Buy my book!
来买我的书
Buy my book,
不然就没有了 各位
before it's too late, people!
想跟我单挑是吧 比尔?
You want a piece of me, Bill?
- 想把我剥个精光? 我恭候大驾 - 哇哦
- You want to get naked? I'm ready! - Wow.
采访结束了
Interview is over!
你看起来就像个傻瓜
You're sounding like a pinhead, agent.
- 我给你个忠告吧 - 都结束了 懂不懂?
- And I've got a suggestion for you. - It's over. Understand?
赶快去看医生
Damage control.
- 达奇 - 你们明显惹恼了西蒙斯先生
- Dutch! - You have obviously upset Mr. Simmons!
23秒之内你们必须离开这里
You have 23 seconds to leave the property.
我已经叫警察了
I have called the police!
你们这群乡巴佬真是自不量力
You are peasant people throwing rocks at a giant!
接下来呢 有什么安排?
What's up next? What have we got?
中午在市中心签售
Book signing, Midtown, noon.
然后和探索频道洽谈您的真人秀节目
Then we pitch your reality show to the Discovery Channel.
哦 还有那个谁
Oh, and I had this...
维特维奇今天给您打了5次电话了
Witwicky who keeps calling me. Five times today.
那小子想干嘛?
Kid? What does he want?
霸天虎又回来了
I called you because the Decepticons are back.
我想求你帮忙查清原因
I want to know why, and I need your help.
他们回来了?
They're back?
这下又有钱赚了
Well, that's good for business.
想不想知道一个 隐藏了50年的外星机密
What if I told you I know a 50-year-old alien secret.
没人知道的秘密
that nobody ever told you.
求你别再引诱我
Do not tempt my addiction.
我已经金盆洗手了 孩子
I have gone through withdrawal, kid.
达奇 这条线路安全吗?
Dutch, is this line secure?
不
No.
别冒险
Don't take the risk.
我现在有钱了 我图什么啊?
I'm rich, why should I?
不要再复出了 绝不能
Do not relapse. I won't.
别让让心中的恶魔卷土重来
Do not let the demons win.
可以了
Got it.
什么样的...机密?
What kind of... secret?
阿波罗 月亮 外星人 伪装
Apollo. Moon. Aliens. Cover-up.
未来技术 暗杀 这类的机密
Future tech. Assassinations. That kind of stuff.
哦 阿波罗
Oh, Apollo.
达奇
Dutch!
告诉威震天 哥重出江湖了
Tell Megatron, "Let's tango".
这颗星球多么壮丽而祥和啊
So majestic and peaceful, this planet.
哪像塞伯坦的末日景象
Unlike the final days of Cybertron.
我曾经想过
I've wondered what might have been.
当初若是由您来指挥最后一战
if you had fought the final battle,
不是我
instead of me.
别追悔过去 年轻的战士
Never mourn the past, young warrior.
多亏了你 我们的种族才得以延续
Thanks to you, our race survives.
您曾是我们的超级领袖 御天敌
You were our leader, Sentinel.
您有权再次领导我们
It is your right to lead us again.
在这个我不熟悉的世界
In a world I do not know,
我不再是你的老师了 擎天柱
I am no longer your teacher, Optimus.
你才是
You are mine.
这事得查个水落石出
You've got to break this case down.
宇航员倒霉也能传染
What we have here is an astronaut epidemic.
失踪 死亡 交通事故 谋杀 送医不治 车祸
MIA. Dead. Died in a car accident. Killed. DOA. Car death.
就像是这些家伙不会开车 但却能都让飞船开上天
It's like these guys can't drive. They can fly into outer space,
居然开不好车
but they can't drive a car.
这是你要的情报 维特维奇
Procured your information, Witwicky.
谢谢你 布鲁斯
Thank you, Bruce.
慢着
Now,
让我看一眼 就这一次
Let me see one right now. One time.
- 要快 - 没问题
- Quick. - Very.
探月轨道飞行器
Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter.
国家航空航天局于2009年发射
It says NASA launched it in 2009.
庭审记录显示 杰瑞可能篡改了代码
See, forensics show Wang may have messed with the code,
导致无法测绘月球远端
preventing it from mapping the far side of the moon,
也就是月球背面
which is also the dark side.
太酷了
Fucking awesome.
他们搞渗透 搞恐吓
They infiltrate us, intimidate us,
逼迫人类给他们干肮脏勾当
coerce us to do their dirty work.
一旦事成呢?
And once they're done,
砰 砰
Dushhhh.
就毫不犹豫杀人灭口
a double-tap to the cerebellum.
也就是说 有人类在为霸天虎做事
So humans are working for the Decepticons.
我觉得霸天虎
I don't think this is about the Decepticons.
不是在月球上找什么东西
looking for something on the moon.
我觉得他们是...
I think it's about something...
...要隐藏什么
...they wanted to hide.
跟老爸玩玩
Come to Daddy.
来吧 过两招
Come on, throw down.
你小时候是不是脑袋让驴踢了?
Did you eat a lot of paint chips when you were a kid?
真胡闹
He's a freak.
- 哈 喜欢吗? - 后退
- Ha. Like it? - Get back!
我来教你两招...
I'll teach you...
先生
Sir!
我在召开一个外星人情报高端分析会议
We are having a pretty high-level alien intel confab here.
我想你没有资格参加
that I don't think you're cleared for.
- 跑腿的 - 没错 你说得对
- Errand boy. - Yeah, you're right.
- 这机器人真给力 - 布鲁斯 你该走了
- It's a bitching robot. - I think it's time to go, Bruce.
多谢你让我开了眼界
Thank you so much for this. And...
走吧 布鲁斯
Got to go, Bruce.
嘿 我忙得浑身冒烟
Hey, I'm smokin' over here.
关于那些失踪的苏联宇航员
Now with the missing Russian cosmonauts.
前苏联曾经取消了一次载人登月计划
Turns out the Soviets canceled a manned mission to the moon.
那是1972年的事
The moon, in 1972.
后来其中两名宇航员潜逃到了美国
And two of their cosmonauts went into hiding in America.
我刚刚发现了他们
And I just found them alive.
你真是个天才 小诸葛
You're a genius, Brains.
看你干的好事 大黄蜂
That was smooth, Bumblebee.
就差那么一点
Missed it by that much.
嗨
Hi.
谁能告诉我这是怎么回事?
Would somebody care to tell me what the hell's going on?
你是谁?
Who are you?
- 你是谁? - 居然问我?
- Who are you? - Who am I?
那谁...达奇 搜她的身
Who is that? Dutch! Frisk her!
遵命
Certainly.
等等
No.
达奇
Dutch.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
- 我也没打算碰你 - 山姆
- I'm not gonna touch you. - Sam.
宝贝
Angel.
我在工作
Uh, I was working.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry about this.
太好了 又要无家可归了
Great. We're homeless.
她住在这里?
She lives here?
哇
Wow.
你真该搜她身
You had your chance to frisk her.
我有女友的
I have a girlfriend.
是吗? 那她叫什么?
Really? What's her name?
印蒂亚
Innn...dia.
我们要去参加迪伦的晚会 忘了吗?
We're supposed to be at Dylan's party, remember?
我没忘 但这些人是我的朋友
I do remember, but these are my friends.
他们需要我 我现在走不开
They need me. I have to be here right now.
那又怎样? 汽车人和军方
So, what, the Autobots and the military,
不能自己解决问题吗?
they can't handle this on their own?
知道我为什么喜欢你的战争故事吗?
You know what I liked about your war stories, Sam?
因为它们仅仅是故事而已
It's that they were stories,
都过去了
they were in the past.
听着 我知道你又想起你牺牲的哥哥
Look, I know you're thinking about your brother, okay?
在想你的家人
And you're thinking about your family.
但现在情况不同
And it's not that situation.
- 不同吗? - 很不同
- No? - No.
有什么不同?
Why not?
告诉我怎么不同?山姆
Why isn't it, Sam?
你觉得我们拿奖章好
You think we'd rather have his medals,
还是看到他活着好?
or we'd rather have him?
你说得对 我明白了
I hear you. I get it.
你要带我的幸运兔去哪? 站住
Where are you taking my bunny? Stop!
求你先别走
Just stop for a second.
你以为我昨晚能睡得着吗?
You think I could sleep last night?
我总算想明白了 山姆就是喜欢冒险
And then it hit me. No, Sam wants to be in danger.
不然他都不知道自己是谁了
He doesn't know who he is without it.
我只想让你看得起我
I just want to matter.
我看得起你
You matter to me.
我知道你很担心 你非常担心我
I know you're worried. I know you're worried.
但我向你保证 我会照顾好自己
But I promise you, I can handle this.
你能保证吗?
Can you? You can promise it?
我保证
I promise.
山姆 我不想失去你 我知道结果会怎样
Sam, I don't want to lose you, and I know where this leads.
我还没心理准备
I'm not ready for this.
你跟我一起去吗?
Are you coming with me?
我不能
I can't.
好吧
Okay.
嘿
Hey.
你的兔脚
Here's your foot.
真正的勇士总是独来独往
The warrior's path is a solitary one.
天啊 她怎么买得起那种车?
How the hell did she afford that car?
- 老板送的 - 有钱的混蛋
- Her boss. - Rich bastards!
以前我也讨厌他们
I used to hate them.
现在嘛...
Now, it's...
我们去黑帮追查两名前苏联宇航员
Going to a gig on the hunt for two Russian cosmonauts.
什么也比不上开迈巴赫拉风 是吧?
Nothing like driving in a Maybach.
德国人造的车没得说
Germans know how to make cars, let me tell you.
我的小达奇 原国家安全局的网络讯息高手
My Dutchman, former NSA cybersleuth extraordinaire,
他查到他们就在这里
tracked them down here.
为什么这些宇航员要躲藏起来? 为什么?
So, these cosmonautswent into hiding. Why?
发现目标 完全吻合
Bingo. I got a match.
达奇 你真是头德国牧羊犬
You're a German Shepherd, Dutch.
俄国人有个毛病
The thing about Russians is,
就是不爱多说话
they never like to talk.
得用点国际通用语
It's gonna take a little of the "international language".
- 等会见 - 那意思是再见
- Dos vedanya. - That means "good-bye".
来点带劲的
Give a spunky remark.
没问题
No problem.
谁来引领革命
Who's to get revolution.
一个名人
A famous.
达奇
Dutch.
给我来句狠话
Give me something tough.
- 巴雷什尼科夫 - 我们会说英语
- Baryshnikov. - We do speak English.
达奇 你真丢人
Dutch, you suck.
全是斯拉夫语
It's a Cyrillic.
都是字母
alphabet.
就像高级电脑上那些生僻按键
It's like all the buttons you never push on a calculator!
我才不丢人呢
I don't suck.
我是西摩·西蒙斯特工来自第8区 过去的第7区
Agent Seymour Simmons, Sector Eight, formerly Seven.
我们知道你们是谁
We know who you are,
前苏联宇航员
cosmonautchiks.
那又怎样?
So what?
你们本来要执行一次登陆月球背面的任务
You were supposed to travel to the dark side of the moon,
但最终任务取消了
then it all got shut down.
我们想知道...
The question is,
为什么?
why?
这三个人脑子有毛病吗?
Are these three people out of their mind?
谁放他们进来的?
Who let them in?
“我的孩子能在这里抽烟吗?”
"Can my child smoke in here?"
这些人我都不认识
I don't know these people.
他们怎么进来的?
How did they come in?
我怎么知道?
How did I know?
快叫人来 快快
Come, come, quick up.
动手
Do it.
好 没问题 好
Okay, all right. Okay.
来啊 开枪啊
Go ahead, shoot me.
你来这里想干什么?
What do you want form here?
我可以为国捐躯 你行吗?
I'm willing to die for my country. Are you?
你给我闭嘴 老实滚出去
You shut up, and get fuck off.
真的吗?
Really?
你想干嘛? 自以为了不起啊
What do you want? You think you're hero?
别动
Don't move.
你真美
You are beautiful.
有人说过你很美吗?
Has anyone ever told you you're beautiful?
因为她就是个美人
'Cause she's a beautiful woman.
别动
Don't move.
哇哦 嘿
Wow... Hey!
达奇 给我乖一点
Dutch! Back in the cage.
达奇
Dutch!
住手 达奇 住手
Hold, Dutch, hold!
管好你的人 别让他乱来
Control your boy, please. Control your boy.
达奇 住手
Dutch, stop!
否则今晚回去跪搓板
Or back to kneel washboard tonight.
真抱歉 刚才是过去的我
I'm so sorry. That is the old me.
好了 大家都冷静下来
Okay, let's everybody just calm down!
让我们都把枪放下 放轻松
Let's lower the heat, lower the guns. Let's relax.
二战已经结束了
World War II is over.
你们即将看到前苏联最重要的机密之一
You are about to see one of the biggest Soviet secrets.
美国第一个把人类送上了月球
America first to send man to the moon.
但苏联却是抢先把照相机送了上去
But USSR first to send camera.
1959年 我们的月球3号
In 1959, our Luna 3.
拍摄了月球背面的照片
take picture of the dark, the shadow side.
空无一物
Sees nothing.
但到了1963年 月球4号发现了...
But in 1963, Luna 4 sees...
奇怪的石堆
Strange rocks.
- 对 - 就在飞船周围
- Yeah. - Around the ship.
有好几百块
Hundreds of them.
给他们看照片
Yeah, show picture.
还有些拖拽的痕迹
With some drag marks.
我见过这个 这些不是石头
I've seen these. These aren't rocks,
是能量柱
these are pillars.
用来建造太空桥的能量柱
Alien pillars for a space bridge.
我们知道这些 是因为汽车人手里有五根
We know about them because the Autobots have five of these.
霸天虎一定搜查过整条船
The Decepticons must have raided the ship before
在阿波罗11号抵达之前
Apollo 11 ever got there,
拿走了能量柱 并藏了起来
took the pillars, and hid them.
但这不合逻辑 既然霸天虎找到了飞船
It doesn't make sense. The Decepticons have the ship.
也拿走了全部能量柱 那为什么偏偏留下了
They have all those pillars. Why would they leave Sentinel.
唯一会使用它们的御天敌呢?
when he's the only one who can use them?
除非...
Unless...
他就是霸天虎仍然觊觎的目标
He's the one thing they still need.
我们得赶紧去找御天敌
We've got to meet up with Sentinel,
守在他身旁 保卫他的安全
rendezvous with him and keep him safe.
梅琳 我刚刚找到御天敌 擎天柱10分钟后就到
Mearing, I just picked up Sentinel. Optimus is 10 minutes behind.
我们正在返回NEST
We're coming to NEST now.
维特维奇先生 我提醒过你
Mr. Witwicky, I thought I made it clear to you.
不要再打这个电话了
that I did not want you calling this phone.
听着 整件事都是个陷阱
Listen, the whole thing has been a setup since the beginning.
霸天虎希望擎天柱找到御天敌
The Decepticons wanted Optimus to find Sentinel.
因为只有擎天柱才能复活他
because only Optimus could revive him.
但太空桥在我们手中
But we have the space bridge.
梅琳 你手中只有5个能量柱
Mearing, you have five pillars.
我刚刚得知霸天虎有几百个
I just learned that they have hundreds.
你是在被他们牵着鼻子走
You're doing exactly what they wanted you to do.
我要跟你说的是...
What do you need me to say to you?
霸天虎很快就会来找御天敌
The Decepticons are coming for Sentinel Prime!
我们马上出发去NEST
We're going to NEST.
能量警报
We have an Energon alert.
在华盛顿州际公路上发现能量讯号...
Energon readings detected on the D. C. Parkway.
正在追踪
Currently tracking.
三辆黑色越野车
three black Suburbans.
大黄蜂 你掩护御天敌离开这里
Bee, you got to get Sentinel out of here! You got to guard him!
噢 天啊 我要被炒鱿鱼了
Oh, mein Gott! I'm fired!
当心 当心 当心
Watch out! Watch out! Watch out!
抓住你了
Got you!
射击 射击
Shoot him! Shoot him!
干掉他 大黄蜂
Shoot him, Bee!
大黄蜂 再开快点 再快 快
Bee, you've got to move faster! Faster, Bee! Go!
大黄蜂 快
Bee, faster!
好了 回NEST
All right, back to NEST!
恐龙 我来对付他
Dino, I got him!
铁皮
Ironhide!
有什么问题吗?
Is there a problem?
哇哦 搞得跟西部片对决一样
A little Mexican standoff we got here.
放下武器
Weapons down.
我们会让你们体面地离开
And we'll let you escape with your dignity.
丢掉武器
Drop them.
很好
That's good.
铁皮 当心
Ironhide, watch out!
铁皮 接枪
Ironhide, catch!
当心背后
Behind you!
霸天虎小混混
Decepticon punk!
管教完毕
Class dismissed.
- 都进去 快 - 快点
- Get inside! Let's go! - Move!
行动 动作快
Keep moving!
- 伦诺克斯 - 行动 行动
- Lennox! - Go, go, go!
到处都是霸天虎
We got Decepticons everywhere.
我已经派出全部人马去搜捕他们了
I've got my whole team deployed looking for them.
铁皮
Ironhide!
保护御天敌 带他到里面去
Protect Sentinel! Get him locked up inside!
包在我身上
Consider it done.
你要保卫好他 他是整件事的关键
Hey, you've got to guard him, 'cause he's the key to the whole thing.
说得没错
Indeed, I am.
汽车人兄弟们 你们必须意识到
What you must realize, my Autobot brothers,
我们当年根本赢不了那场战争
is we were never going to win the war.
为了保住我们的母星
For the sake of our planet's survival,
我不得不和威震天...
a deal had to be made...
做了笔交易
with Megatron.
退后
Get back!
你这是干什么?
What have you done?
我马上就让你解脱
I hereby discharge you from duty.
- 大黄蜂 - 退后
- Bee! - Get back!
NEST全部人马撤回基地
Rally all NEST forces back to the base!
- 快 - 不...
- Come on! - No...
快 快
Come on, come on.
叫个医疗兵来
Get a medic down here!
我们人手不足
We don't have enough men!
不要和御天敌硬碰硬
Do not engage Sentinel!
我们走后门
Just go to the back gate.
趴下
Take cover!
前进 前进
Watch left! Watch left!
快点 跟我来
Let's go! Follow me!
过来
come on.
快
Come on.
快 快 快
move move move.
- 等等 - 退后
- Director, don't go there! - Stand down!
嘿 御天敌
Hey, Sentinel!
- 局长 - 出什么事了?
- Director - What is going on?
你这是在干什么?
What do you think you are doing?
我是个首领
I am a Prime!
不会听命于你
I do not take orders from you.
梅琳主任 我们打不过他 撤退吧
Director Mearing, come on. We can't fight him. Let's go.
我们必须离开
We have to go.
把我的东西还给我
Now return what belongs to me!
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my God!
- 大家都还好吗? - 都出去了吗?
- You guys okay? - Is everybody out?
大家保持镇静 马上就没事了
Everybody, stay calm. You're gonna be fine.
你看看 擎天柱
Yeah, take a look, Optimus!
这都是你的错
This is all on you!
御天敌破坏了仓库
Sentinel hit the vault!
把能量柱抢走了
Took the pillars.
快 我们走
Come on, let's go.
好了 通知101空降师
All right, notify the 101St Airborne!
我们得抓住那个家伙
We need to hunt this thing down!
卡莉
Carly!
篝火弄的 热乎乎的
Hot from our little campfire.
夹心巧克力饼
S'mores.
太好了 简直是在世外桃源
Isn't that great? We're really living off the land.
妈爸 见到卡莉回家了吗?
Mom, Dad, have you guys seen Carly come home yet?
我说 你就不会敲门吗?
Excuse me. Can you knock, please?
这是我们的卧室
This is our bedroom.
她难道会不回家吗?
Why wouldn't she be at home?
我们吵架了
We had a fight.
或许分手了
and we might have broken up,
也可能只是暂时分开 我不太清楚
or be on a break. I don't really know.
- 什么? 不 - 我不想谈这事
- What? No. - Look, I can't talk about it right now.
- 妈 我不想谈细节 我必须找到她 - 你在开玩笑吧
- I can't go into details, Mom. I have to find her. - Kiding me?
坐下 我们开个家庭会议
Sit down. We're having a family meeting.
正式的家庭会议
Family meeting!
也许你不知道
You may not know this,
其实我和你爸也不是一直这么恩爱
but your father and I were not always this perfectly happy.
结婚这些年来 我也曾想过
You know, there was a time in our marriage.
我没法和这人生活下去了
when I thought this was not gonna work out.
拜托 请别说了
please, Can we please not?
- 我不明白你怎么能... - 她真伤我的心
- I'm just you understand - She's damaging him.
...和一个世界级美女分手
You break up with one world-class hottie...
别说了 停下好吧?
No. Stop. Stop, okay?
她甩了我 我再去找个更好的
She dumped me, I moved on to something better.
不就行了吗? 我还更幸福呢
That's it. I'm a happier person.
这已经是第二个美人了
The second beautiful girl.
帮我一把
Why don't you help me?
又失去它她?
lose her?
- 他们只是发生争执 - 是打架了
- They had an argument. - One fight.
好吧 可是你找不到第三个了
Okay, but you're not going to get a third one.
我是说除非你那个很大...
I mean unless you have like a big...
什么乱七八糟的... 老妈 别说了
What the F... Mom, mom, mom!
你大概都不知道自己在干什么
I mean you just don't know what you're doing.
- 我不想再说了 - 你需要读读书
- I don't want to talk about this anymore. - You need the book.
男人永远是错的 记着这句话
You're always wrong. Get used to it.
就这本 你拿去好好读一读
Okay. You've gotta read this.
在《女人至上》这本书中 对付女人的招术
She Comes First. here's some killer shit in here.
不 不
No. No.
- 不 - 哦 又来了
- No. - That's it, I'm going.
不 不
No! No!
坐下 坐下 替我说几句
Sit down, sit down! Back me up!
老婆开心 生活舒心
Happy wife, happy life.
- 没错 - 老婆不满
- Yeah. - Unhappy wife,
那就余生悲惨咯...
stone-cold misery for the rest of your...
- 闭嘴 - 这是实话
- Stop. - It's true.
我想说的是
All I'm saying is,
你爱这女孩吗?
do you love this girl?
这辈子就认她了
She's the one.
那就去把她追回来
Then you gotta go get her.
告诉你 你爸和我吵架的时候
I mean, your dad and I, when we had troubles,
他会不惜一切去找我
he moved heaven and earth to find me.
告诉他你当时怎么说的
Would he, say what you said.
- 快说 - “我会陪你到地老天荒”
- Say it. - "I will follow you to the end of time".
听起来很傻吧
Does that suck or what?
- 就像狗屎爱情剧一样 - 不 很浪漫啊
- It's like a bad sci-fi film. - No. It is so sweet.
你们得离开这个城市
I want you to get out of the city.
走得越远越好
You get as far away from here as you can.
明白吗?
You understand?
我爱你们
I love you.
哦 主人
Oh, my master.
多么完美的计划
Such a brilliant scheme!
原来御天敌离开塞伯坦时
So when Sentinel left Cybertron,
就已经是叛徒了
it was to defect?
他本该和我在地球会合
He was meant to rendezvous with me here on Earth.
谁知命运使我们擦肩而过
before fate waylaid us both.
复活他的唯一途径
The only way to revive him,
就是擎天柱和他的领导模块
we needed Prime and his Matrix.
高 实在是高
Excellent strategy.
我的 我的
Mine, mine!
他现在是您的伙伴了 主人
So he is now your partner, master?
他是我最伟大的战利品
He is my greatest triumph.
我对您五体投地
So impressive.
开始传输
Commencing transport.
住手 不要 御天敌
Stop! No! No, Sentinel!
原谅我
Forgive me.
我们来了
Here we are.
和我们战斗吧
Fight us now.
保持联系
Contact!
小心 走 走
Watch out! Move it! Move it!
汽车人 撤退
Autobots, retreat!
为什么 御天敌 为什么?
Why, Sentinel, why?
为了塞伯坦
For Cybertron!
为了我们的家园
For our home!
战争的破坏我们可以修复
What war destroyed, we can rebuild!
但必须和霸天虎合作
But only if we join with the Decepticons.
不 还有别的方法
No, it's not the only way.
这里才是我们的家
This is our home!
我们必须保护人类
We must defend the humans!
你误入歧途了 擎天柱
So lost you are, Optimus.
在塞伯坦 我们被敬若神明
On Cybertron, we were gods.
在这里 地球人却叫我们“机器”
And here, they call us machines.
人类要么成为我们的奴仆
Let the humans serve us,
要么就灭亡
or perish.
我没杀你算你走运
You're lucky I didn't kill you.
将来你会明白的
In time you'll see.
这还不算完
It's not over.
如果我是他
Now, if I were him,
我一秒钟都不会让你离开我的视线
I wouldn't let you out of my sight for one second.
有意思 来这的路上我一直琢磨
It's funny. I was just thinking on the way over here,
我真的需要迪伦给点建议
I could really use some advice from Dylan, and there he is.
- 而他就在这里 能跟你谈谈吗? - 欢迎
- Can I speak to you, Carly? - Welcome.
请坐 喝杯酒吧
Please, sit down. Have a drink.
老实说 我不想喝酒
You know what, I don't need a drink.
也不在乎车子 工作
Or a car, or a job.
我就想和我女友单独谈谈
I just need to speakto my girlfriend alone.
你不会介意吧 电灯泡先生?
Is that okay with you, Mr. Inappropriate?
不好意思
Excuse me.
- 出什么事了? - 到外面再说
- What's going on? - I'll tell you outside.
我认为我能帮你 山姆
I really think I can help you, Sam.
我曾和父亲探讨如何做出抉择
I remember a talk I had with my dad once about tough choices.
可惜现在不是时候 咱们回头再聊
Yeah, now's not the time. We'll set something up, though.
当然那是很久以前了 那时我父亲的公司还在
Of course, it was way back, when my dad's firm was in charge.
为国家航空航天局做经费预算和财务报表
of budget review and accounting for NASA.
他教给我的是
You see, the thing that he taught me was,
如果这战争与你无关
when it's not your war,
那就最好站在能赢的那方
you join the side that's going to win.
走
Move.
太直接了 我的老毛病?
Too direct? Or is it just me?
一点也不
Certainly not you, sir.
你是我的了
You're mine!
不
No!
来人啊
Get help!
- 山姆 我不能出来 - 谁来救救她
- Sam, I can't get out! - Someone get help!
- 晚安 - 晚安 迪伦先生
- Good night! - Good night, Mr. Dylan.
山姆 救我出去
Get me out of here!
救命
Help!
救救她
Get help!
他还年轻 早晚会明白的
He's young. He will learn.
- 救我出去 - 晚安
- Get me out! - Good night.
今晚很愉快
It was a fun night.
你以为自己是第一个
You really think you're the first man ever.
涉足外星人事务的人吗?
asked to join the noble alien cause?
你到底是谁?
Who are you?
你知道为什么1972年之后 我们再也没有登月吗?
Do you know why we've not been back to the moon since 1972?
因为这两位
Because these two,
他们来找我父亲
they came to my dad.
要求他伪造一些账目
and they told him to do some creative accounting.
拼命拔高登月预算
Make it way too expensive to ever go back.
所以 他和其他人
So, he and the others.
终止了美俄两国的太空计划
shut down the American and Russian space programs.
自此这二位便成为了我们的客户
And they've been our clients ever since.
你帮他们杀人?
You helped them kill people?
你以为我有得选择吗?
You think they'd give you a choice?
再说 我个人也没有参与
Besides, it's not like I personally participated.
我只是个联络人
I am a liaison.
只负责传话
I liaise.
该是坏人出场的时候了 山姆
It's hostile takeover time, Sam.
山姆
Sam!
放她走
Let her go!
山姆
Sam!
我监视你很多年了 山姆
I've had my eye on you for years, Sam.
而你是个间谍 我一直无法在
You're the one spy I've never been able to provide.
在汽车人身边安插间谍
as someone close to the Autobots.
山姆 别照他说的做
Sam! Don't do what he wants!
他会的
Yes, he will.
他们都会
They all do.
他们会杀了她 你懂吗?
They will slaughter her, you understand me?
只要一眨眼的功夫
In the time it takes you to blink,
他们就会杀了她 然后杀了我
they'll do it to her and they'll do it to me.
所以 你至少该尊重下
So you show a little respet.
那个给你推荐工作的人
when someone offers you a job!
手腕
Wrist.
你要去找擎天柱
You are to track down Optimus Prime,
因为在人类中他最信任你
because you're the one human he trusts,
你要问他一个问题
and you will ask one question.
他打算如何反击?
How does he intend to fight back?
什么策略 什么战术 全都给我套出来
Strategies, tactics, everything!
咬得够狠吧 对不对?
Has a nasty little bite, doesn't it?
这可是高科技
It's very high-tech.
它能让我们看你所看 听你所听
It lets us see what you see, hear what you hear.
还能介入你的神经系统
and it taps your nervous system.
所以你不要妄想警告其他人
So, if you so much as try and signal...
我要告诉你 山姆
I don't know what to tell you, Sam.
有果就有因
Relationships have consequences.
我站在这儿是因为我父亲 她待在这儿是因为你
I am here because of my father. She is here because of you.
住手 住手 住手 住手
Stop, stop! Stop! Stop!
震荡波 收敛点行吗?
Soundwave, would you please?
山姆
Sam,
你乖乖办事
do your job.
她会没事的 我向你保证
She'll be safe. I give you my word.
我会杀了你
I'll kill you.
我也向你保证
You have my word.
指挥中心已发布一级战备状态
Combatant Commands are now at DEFCON 1.
世界各地潜伏着大约两百个霸天虎
Approximately 200 Decepticons are now in hiding.
甚能量都检测到存在
Energon detectors have been triggered.
甚至远在南美和中国的能量
as far away as South America and China.
联合国刚刚收到一份加密音频文件
The U. N. Just received an encrypted audio file.
是来自汽车人的超级领袖
They say it's from the leader of the Autobots.
地球的保卫者们
Defenders of Earth.
我们来到这里寻求自然资源
We have come for your natural resources.
以重建我们满目疮痍的母星
to rebuild our damaged planet.
我们的所有要求得到满足后
When we have transported all we need,
就会和平地离开地球
we will leave your world in peace.
为了保证这份和平
For such peace to exist,
你们必须立即驱逐已收留的汽车人叛逆
you must immediately exile the Autobot rebels you have harbored.
没有谈判的余地
Nonnegotiable.
立即驱逐那些叛逆
Renounce the rebels.
我们等候你们的答覆
We await your reply.
我们会跟进你的情报
We'll debrief you in transit.
我不知道能帮什么忙
Yeah, I really don't see how I can be of any help.
再说你们也挺忙的
I mean, you guys seem pretty busy.
我们可以下次再谈
We could just do this another time, I think.
看来我过去真是低估了你了
I have underestimated you at every turn.
什么?
What?
你提醒过我们 他们在利用人类
You warned us that they were using humans.
也说过御天敌是全局的关键
And you knew that Sentinel was the key.
主任
Director!
我算啥啊? 你们才是专家
Who am I? Hey, you're the expert.
我只是一个四处走动的危险家伙
I'm just a walking security risk.
天哪
God.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
没事
Yes.
- 不对 你出了很多汗 - 真的 我没事
- No, you're not. You're sweating. - I'm fine. I'm fine.
真的没事 我出汗是因为紧张
I'm sweating because I'm nervous.
我紧张是因为你把这些讯息告诉给我
I'm nervous because you got me in here with this information.
我特别喜欢用推特 什么秘密都会写到博客上
Okay, I'm a Twitter junkie. I blog everything.
- 哦 你不敢的 - 真的 我不骗你
- I can't keep a secret to save my life. - You wouldn't dare.
- 要是你敢的话... - 主任 15号线有你的电话
- That's the truth. I'm telling you. - Director, the Pentagon's calling in 15.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
没什么 你在干什么?
Nothing. What are you doing?
离我远点
Get away from me.
今天 在国会发生的事件具有重大意义
It's been a remarkable series of events today at the Capitol.
就在不久之前 国会通过法案
Just moments ago, legislation was passed.
决定将汽车人驱逐出美国领土
to exile the Autobots from American shores.
而他们与美国的军事同盟也正式宣告结束
The U.S. Military alliance with them is officially over.
- 议会和政府的... - 是的
- In the words of the House Majority Leader... - Yeah.
主要负责人就本次决议回答了提问
the sponsor of today's resolution,
- 好的 - 我们的良心不允许我们...
- Okay. - "We cannot in good conscience..."
什么?
What?
他们不能这么做 你得告诉他们 他们不能这样做
They can't do this. You gotta tell them. They can't do that.
好的 政府已经下令 行动吧
Okay. It's official. It's a go, people.
汽车人是我们的盟友 我们曾并肩作战 生死与共
These are our allies. The Autobots fought for us. They fought with us.
结果怎么样呢?
And where are we now?
兵临城下
Facing an enemy invasion.
而且敌方兵力无法估量
with an enemy that has the means to deploy countless more.
如果你还知道些什么
If there is any more you know,
任何关于敌人意图的讯息
anything at all about the enemy's intentions,
现在该告诉我了
now is the time to tell.
汽车人没办法离开地球
Autobots have no way of leaving this planet.
你说错了
And that is where you're wrong.
飞船名叫苍耳号
Its name is the Xanthium.
就是它运来了第二批汽车人
It brought the second wave of Autobots.
此后一直由国家航空航天局保管和研究
and it's been under NASA 's care and study ever since.
我们将它和一艘退役航天飞机捆绑
We linked it with a decommissioned shuttle.
使其在汽车人离开之前都处于军方控制之下
to maintain military control until they're gone.
那个脆弱的螺栓将承受到一万磅的扭力
Gonna be 10, 000 pounds of torque on that itsy-bitsy bolt,
这不关我事
Oh, not my thing!
你们是在拿我同伴的生命冒险
You're gonna risk the livesof all me mates!
鄙视你们
I'll ball you!
那是雷霆拯救队 他们负责维护苍耳号
These guys are the Wreckers. They take care of the Xanthium.
我们一般不让他们离开基地 因为他们都不是好鸟
We don't let them off the base much, 'cause they're assholes.
你要用力拉 废物
You gotta pull that, ya nancy swanker!
这么用力会弄坏的
It's torqued to kill them.
我只是在帮你 你懂的 尽点力
I'm just trying to help, you know. Just doing my job.
冷静点
Just calm down.
这是人类不是机器人
Leave him alone. This is a human being.
- 艾普斯 - 你简直不可理喻
- Epps! - You are ridiculous!
真的是你
Is that you?
嗨 伙计
What up, man.
你怎么在这里?
What are you doing here?
我从空军退役了
I retired from the Air Force.
放开我的手行吗?
Can you let my hand go?
你这是怎么了?
What the hell was that?
退役后我来到这儿做顾问和协调工作
Now I just consult to run interference for them.
别乱帮忙行吗?
Well, you're not helping!
不用打仗了 也不用被外星人追杀
No more combat and aliens shooting at my ass.
总算找到了梦寐以求的工作
I got a dream job.
是时候离开这星球了
Time to get off this planet.
他们要把汽车人赶走
Kicking the Autobots out.
你能相信这样的事吗?
Can you believe this is happening?
你知道他们要飞往哪里吗?
Where do you think it's taking them?
总之是地球之外的地方
Any planet but here.
我想和这里的头儿谈谈
I wanna talk to whoever's in charge here!
我还以为是谁呢
Well, well, well.
是夏洛特·梅琳啊
Charlotte Mearing.
西蒙斯探员
Agent Simmons.
前探员西蒙斯
Former Agent Simmons.
看来你没死在华盛顿
So I see you survived Washington.
华盛顿 埃及 失恋
Washington, Egypt, heartbreak.
我都挺过来了 我还会活下去的
I survive. I will survive.
他们正在动员所有的情报人员
They're bringing everybody in, kid.
情报人员正在汇集所有的情报
Putting all the intel on the table.
如果你以为驱逐9个汽车人
And if you think deporting nine Autobots.
就能解决问题的话...
is gonna solve a damn thing...
这事我做不了主
It's out of my hands.
看来你高升了
Moving up in the world?
你的臀部真美
Your booty looks excellent.
你要是敢跟别人
You ever say word to anyone...
说起在匡提科那晚的事
...about what happened that night in Quantico.
我就把你的心掏出来
I'll cut your heart out.
你早就掏走了
You already did.
山姆 听我说
Sammy, listen to me.
- 别让他们驱逐我们 - 别抛弃我们 山姆
- Don't let them exile us. - Don't let them take us, Sam.
这是霸天虎的圈套
It's a Decepticon trap.
检查氮气量 我们准备发射
Check the nitrogen levels. We're booking out of here.
擎天柱
Optimus?
你们的领导人说得对
What your leaders say is true.
这都是我的错
This was all my fault.
我告诉他们谁值得信赖
I told them whom to trust.
实在是大错特错
I was so wrong.
那不怪你 只是这举动更像人类而已
That doesn't make it your fault. It just makes you human for a change.
记住
Remember this.
你们可以对我们失去信心
You may lose your faith in us,
但绝不要对自己失去信心
but never in yourselves.
我想知道你打算如何反击
I need to know how you're gonna fight back.
我知道你一定有策略 我知道...
I know this is strategy, I know you're...
我知道你们会带援军回来
you're coming back with reinforcements, something.
我知道你们有计划...
I know there's a plan...
你可以跟我说 其他人不会知道的
You can tell me. No other human will ever know.
没有计划
There is no plan.
我们要是照他们说的做 到时该如何面对自己呢?
If we just do what they want, how are we gonna live with ourselves?
你是我的朋友 山姆
You are my friend, Sam.
永远都是
You always will be.
但你们的领导人已经做出了决定
But your leaders have spoken.
从现在起
From here,
你们只能孤军奋战了
the fight will be your own.
长话短说
Make it short.
我们要上船了
We're loading up.
好了 动作快点
All right, hustle up!
天亮就发射
We're launching at dawn.
我们会尽自己所能
We're gonna do whatever we can.
让地球得到保护
Make it like it was.
你永远是我的朋友
You will always be my friend,
山姆
Sam.
我该走了
I gotta be going on.
多年以后 若子孙们问起
Years from now, they're gonna ask us,
当年地球被占领的时候 你们在哪里?
"Where were you when they took over the planet?"
我们只能说
We're gonna say,
我们只是站在那里袖手旁观
"We just stood by and watched".
(早上6点30分)
你真的应当把这看成是一种合作关系
You should really look at this as a partnership.
你就应该顺应潮流
You have to stand on the side of progress.
如果你想被载入史册
if you wanna be a part of history.
6...5...4...3...2
six, five, four, three, two,
1...0
one, zero.
发射成功全速推进
Go ahead and throttle up.
你想要答案 你已经拿到了
You wanted an answer. You got one.
我想要的都能到手 山姆
I always get what I want, Sam.
我们只是想确认一下
We just needed to be sure.
确认什么?
Sure of what?
他们乖乖上路了
That they would go without a fight.
- 再说一遍 - 探测到不明目标
- Say again. - Tracking an incoming object.
我们现在都是在为霸天虎卖命
We all work for the Decepticons now.
(伊利诺伊州 芝加哥市)
我需要你帮忙追踪一个电话
I need your help to track a phone call.
电话那头的人
There's a man on this phone.
是霸天虎的人类代表
He's the head of their human operations.
他们抓走了我的女友卡莉
and he has Carly hostage.
你给我坐好了 别动
I want you to sit down. Don't move.
他马上就开过来
I'm watching him drive up right now.
电话是在路上打出的
The call was placed en route.
我现在要侵入手机摄像头
I'm hacking into the phone's camera now.
看 这是摄像头的实时画面
There, that's it. That's a live stream from the camera.
这地方我来确定手机通讯基站位置
Someplace... Hold on. I can triangulate this.
确认 是芝加哥的基站
Okay, it's Chicago cell sites.
那里 找到了 特朗普大厦 在芝加哥 矮的那栋
There, I've got it. Trump Tower, Chicago. Lower penthouse.
准备好了
We're on.
- 我要去那里 - 你确定吗?
- I'm going. - You sure?
谢谢你帮了我 我15个小时之内要赶到
She's done nothing but try to help me, and I can be there in 15 hours.
不能让你一个人去
You're not going alone.
NEST的总部那里还有我的老战友
I still got my NEST friends out there.
我会召集起他们 找到你的女友
I'll round them up, we'll find your girlfriend,
然后逮住那家伙
we're gonna bring this guy in.
你为什么要帮我?
Why are you helping me?
因为那个混账也害死了我的朋友
'Cause that asshole killed my friends, too.
他们说想要地球的资源
They said they were here for our resources,
重建他们的星球
to rebuild their planet.
没错 但事实上只需要一种资源
Yes, but really one resource in particular.
我们星球上独一无二的资源
One unique to our planet.
人类?
Us?
你很聪明
You're very smart.
没有劳动力他们无法重建家园
You see, they can't rebuild without a slave labor force.
有哪个星球能提供60亿工人呢?
How many rocks up there in the universe offer six billion workers?
你什么意思?
What are you talking about?
那么多人 能运走吗?
We can't transport people.
用不着把人带走
They're not shipping people.
他们会把星球运到这里来
They're shipping their planet here.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
御天敌在这里干什么?
What's Sentinel doing here?
看吧
Watch.
他们将数百能量柱放置在全球各地
They're spreading hundreds of pillars around the globe right now.
几个小时后
In just a few hours,
等它们被发射到轨道上启动后
they're gonna launch them into orbit.
就会将塞伯坦传送到我们的世界
and bring Cybertron into our atmosphere.
红色的那根是主控柱
The red one there controls the rest.
一旦激活 传输就将全面启动
He triggers that, it starts the whole thing.
滚开 小肉虫 你的任务已经结束了
Be gone, insect operative. Your work is done.
- 遵命 阁下 - 他真是个混蛋
- Your Excellency. - He's such a dick.
- 你希望悲剧发生吗? - 我只希望能活着 多活40年
- You want this to happen? - I want to survive. I want 40 more years.
你以为我想这样啊?
You think I asked for this?
这都是客户要求
I inherited a client.
是啊 等塞伯坦来了 人类全成了奴隶
Yeah, and when Cybertron's here and we're all their slaves,
估计到时也需要个工头吧
I guess they'll still need a human leader.
少咒我 想活命就听我的
Don't jinx me. You want to survive, you listen to me.
该让地球上的奴隶们认识他们的新主子了
It is time for the slaves of Earth to recognize their masters.
封锁全城
Seal off the city.
把狗都牵出来 带到后面去
Get the dogs outta here now! Get them in the back!
我想他们没告诉你还有这计划吧?
I guess they didn't tell you about this part, did they?
我也不是每场会议都参加的
You think I'm at every meeting?
我在这里很安全
Look, I'm safe.
他们答应过我
They said I was safe.
上路
Let's roll!
刚才还有讯号
We had a signal earlier.
现在一点也没了
It's not working.
现在播送全国紧急广播
This is a national emergency broadcast.
芝加哥遭受了猛烈的攻击
Chicago has suffered a massive attack.
跑错路了
Wrong way!
快掉头 回去
Get out of here! Go back!
一批外星人飞船包围了芝加哥
There is a ring of alien ships around Chicago.
我们的远程轰炸机刚刚被击落
Our high-range bombers were just knocked out of the sky.
他们无法突破城市上空 敌人的空中防线
They can 't get through enemy air defenses over the city.
我们的卫星也受到干扰
Our satellites have been jammed.
无法监控敌人的行动
We have no way to monitor the enemy's movement.
NEST的所有部队 在空军基地待命
Our old NEST teams are on stand-down holding at Grissom Air Force Base.
距战区有10分钟路程
We're about 10 minutes from the battle zone.
特种部队正在试图进入市区
We have Special Forces trying to gain access to the city,
步兵正在外围布控
and infantry is staging at the perimeter.
等等 怎么搞成这样了
Excuse me, excuse me, it just doesn't make sense!
我们就看不到一点画面吗?
Can't we get any eyes in there at all?
我们的侦察机都被击落了
They keep shooting down our drones.
他们把我们变成了瞎子
They want us blind.
但我们还有迷你无人侦察机 可以试试
But we do have a couple of mini-drones we're gonna try.
是谁在管无人侦察机?
Well, whoever's manning these UAV drones,
问他飞机能否改飞特朗普大厦
can we try to redirect them toward Trump Tower?
那孩子 维特维奇正在赶往芝加哥的路上
The kid, Witwickety, was on his way to Chicago.
他说霸天虎的人类间谍 就在那栋大厦里
Said some point-man human op is there for the Decepticons!
听着 如果说我知道什么 我只知道这个
Listen, if I know anything, I know this,
霸天虎祸害到哪里 那小子就跟到哪里
that kid is an alien-bad-news magnet.
我的天啊
My God.
我们要在这样的混乱之城中找到她?
We came here to find her in the middle of all that?
咱们真的要进去吗? 艾普斯?
Are we really going out there, Epps?
我才不去
I'm not going in there.
没人想进去
No one's going in.
我要去
I am.
你们不去 我也要去找她
With or without you, I'll find her.
你这是在找死 山姆
You're gonna get yourself killed, Sam.
你就是想这么做吗?
Is that what you want?
你大老远跑来这里送死?
You came all the way out here to get yourself killed?
是吗? 好好听我说
Huh? Listen to what I'm saying.
她是因为我才被抓来这的 你知道吗?
She's here because of me. Do you understand?
听着 如果你执意要进去
Listen, if you go in this building,
即使她还活着待在里面
that's if she's even still alive,
你也根本找不到她
there's no way you're gonna be able to reach her!
那你说我该怎么办?
What do you suggest I do?
全完了
It's over.
我很抱歉这么说 但真的全完了
I'm sorry, but it's over.
不
No.
嘿 小心
uhp...Incoming!
我们要杀他们个片甲不留
We will kill them all.
雷霆拯救队 废掉他
Wreckers, kill him!
这会很疼
This is going to hurt!
很疼吧
A lot!
你们的领导人不明白
Your leaders will now understand.
霸天虎绝不会放过你们的星球
Decepticons will never leave your planet alone.
因此 我们需要让他们相信我们死了
And we needed them to believe we had gone.
今日 我们以自由的名义
For today, in the name of freedom,
正式向霸天虎宣战
we take the battle to them!
我亲眼目睹你们的飞船爆炸
I saw your ship blow up!
飞船? 我们根本就不在那飞船上
The ship? We were never in the ship!
我们只造船 不坐船
We designed the damn thing, didn't we?
我们都藏在第一节火箭助推器里
We were hidden in the first booster rocket to separate.
然后就按计划降落在大西洋
Splashed down back in the Atlantic, just as planned.
我们哪里也不去
We ain't going nowhere.
是的 没人能赶走我们
Yeah, no one's exiling us.
汽车人要留下来
The Autobots are staying right here.
帮你们赢得战争
We're gonna help you win this war.
他们封锁了城市 形成防御要塞
They're surrounding the city to make a fortress.
所以没人能看到他们在城内的举动
so that no one can see what they're up to inside.
我们唯一的机会就是奇袭
Our only chance is the element of surprise.
我想我知道怎么能看到
I think I know where to look!
迷你无人侦察机 接近特朗普大厦
Mini-drone is on approach to Trump Tower.
你说山姆上那里去了?
You're telling me Sam's headed into that?
可怜的小子
Poor kid.
他可能永远到不了目的地
Probably never got close.
你会开这玩意 对吧?
So, you can fly this thing, right?
什么 那是什么意思?
What is that What is that What is that?
马马虎虎?
So-so?
要是马马虎虎那就太杯具了
So you so-so can fly this. That feels terrible.
我们给你殿后
We're right behind you.
好了 我们突进去
All right, we're going in!
城市已经戒严
The city is secure.
人类已经不可能阻止我们了
The humans cannot stop us.
到下午的时候
As the afternoon falls,
余下的能量柱将到达预定发射地点
the rest of the pillars will reach their launch position.
这就是多年以前 我向你承诺的胜利
This is the victory I promised you so many years ago,
我们将在此携手重建塞伯坦
where we rebuild Cybertron together!
我和你共事
I have deigned to work with you.
只是为了确保我们的星球能幸存下来
that our planet may survive!
但我绝不会为你卖命
I will never work for you!
你最好记住这两者之间的差别
You would be wise to remember the difference.
哦 烦死了 我最讨厌等待
Oh, I'm so sick of this. I'm just sick of waiting.
她在哪里?
Where is she?
你挺有种的
You've got some balls.
不 山姆
No, Sam!
不
No!
不 不
no! no!
卡莉
Carly!
快跳
Jump!
大黄蜂 开火
Bee, fire!
大黄蜂
Oh. Bee!
汽车人 他们还活着
Autobots! They're alive!
而且他们就在这里
They're here.
霸天虎 保卫能量柱
Decepticons, defend the pillar!
升起吊桥
Raise the bridges!
找到他们
Find them!
山姆
Sam.
你找到我了
You found me.
天涯海角我也要找到你
I'd follow you anywhere.
从外围
Form a perimeter!
走吧 快走
Let's go, let's go!
你疯了吗?
Well, you're crazy.
这东西是我们的吗?
What is that? Is that us?
是军队的无人侦察机
This thing's a military UAV.
试试看它能否运作
Stone, check and see if it's still working.
是的 还有动力
Yeah, it's still got power.
飞行控制中心 能接收到吗?
Flight Control, do you copy?
动一下镜头 或者随便做点什么
Can... Can you rotate? Can you do something?
发现情况
I think we got something.
艾普斯 是艾普斯
Epps! We got Epps!
做点什么
Do something.
拜托 快启动 启动
Come on, work! Work!
好了 把音量放大
All right, turn the volume up on that!
是他
The kid!
做点什么 能把镜头转过来吗?
Do something Can you rotate or something?
好的 好的
Yes, yes!
好了 好了 他们能看见我们
Okay, okay, okay. They can see us.
芝加哥现在是中心战场 知道吗?
Chicago is ground zero, do you understand?
- 能听见吗? - 维特维奇
- Can you hear us? - Witwicky.
明白了吗?
You understand?
听好了 御天敌就在这里
Please listen. Sentinel Prime is here.
还有他那些太空桥的零件
and he has the pillars to his space bridge.
他们就在芝加哥河旁边的一栋大楼楼顶
They're on top of a building on Chicago River.
在霍奇基斯·古尔德投资大厦楼顶
It's owned by Hotchkiss Gould Investments.
主控柱是装置的核心
Now, the pillar that controls everything.
就在东南角的穹顶里
is in the southeast cupola.
你们要搞定主控柱 立刻摧毁它
You've got to destroy the pillar. You have to shoot down the pillar.
不然他们就要把塞伯坦传送过来了明白吗?
or they're going to transport Cybertron here, do you understand?
- 明白了吗? - 什么?
- Do you understand? - What?
给我查出那栋建筑和侦察机的GPS座标
Give me a G PS on the building and on that drone!
我们走
Let's go!
正在测量
Mensurate those coordinates.
缩小范围
Shorten the kill chain.
停机坪上的伙计们 给我5分钟
Guys on the tarmac, five minutes.
- 从这里到东南方 - 好了
- The southeast cupola. - All right!
得抢在被敌机发现之前采取行动
We need to move before the fighters spot us.
在这里等着 我们先去探路
Wait here until we scout a route ahead.
出发
Let's roll.
铁皮 掩护高处
Ratchet, cover high.
嘿 你觉得能用火箭弹打下主控柱吗?
Hey, think we could use that rock et to shoot down the pillar?
我们离那里有8个街区远
We're eight blocks away.
想要打中的话 得再接近点
We got to get closer to take a shot.
不用靠近 到高处去
Not closer. Higher.
得确保视野清晰
We need a clear line of sight.
那需要过河
And it's across the river. Gonna have.
很难悄悄潜进去
a hell of a time trying to sneak up.
我们只有一炮的机会
We only got one shot.
一炮就足够了
One shot's all we need.
我们需要看到那幢大厦周围的情况
We got to be able to see around that building from the ground.
联络国家安全局 调来该地区的监视器分布图
Get NSA to send service specs for any cameras in that area.
也许还有能用的
Maybe some are working.
交通灯 提款机 只要带摄像头的都行
Traffic lights. ATMs. Anything.
听好
Listen up.
想反击吗? 那就只能穿滑翔衣飞进去
You want to hit back? We're gonna have to wingsuit in.
这是我们接近那里的唯一方法
It's the only way to get close.
我不能保证跟我去的都能活着回来
I can't promise anyone a ride home, but if you're with me,
但现在世界需要你们
the world needs you now.
我自己能回来 长官
I'll find my own ride home, sir.
还有谁?
Who else?
还有我 长官
I'm, sir.
莫绍尔将军
General Morshower,
请求派兵在城南牵制敌军
requesting diversionary action to the south of the city.
我们从北面降落突入 迫使他们向东转移
We're coming north and low. You guys drive them to the east.
汽车人必胜 汽车人必胜
Autobot victory! Autobot victory!
我得提醒你们 外面的霸天虎真是太恐怖了
I gotta warn you. It's scary out there, Decepticons!
他们夺走了我的车厢 我需要其中的飞行装备
They got my trailer. I need that flight tech.
震荡波无法同时应付我们所有人
Shockwave can't hunt all of us at once.
雷霆拯救队 你们去引开他
Wreckers, we need a diversion.
- 我们去露一手 - 你说的没错
- Let's get some! - You got that right.
听好了 我们要设法进入那栋玻璃幕墙大楼
Listen, we're gonna circle around to that glass building.
到制高点发射火箭炮
And we'll get high enough to make the rocket shot.
你们牵制他的火力 我们走
while you guys draw his fire. Let's move!
等一下
Wait a minute!
不带着我的巷战新武器 我可不会放你们出去
I'm not letting you go out there without my urban combat prototypes.
我们得走了 Q 别闹
We got to go, Que! Come on.
等等嘛 这些可是给高手用的绝妙玩意
Wait, they're great inventions for kicking ass!
这些是什么玩意?
What are these?
那些是爆破棒
Those are boom-sticks.
定时30秒爆炸
Armed in 30 seconds.
还有抓钩手套 可以爬墙
Grapple gloves, for climbing.
出去 快
Go, go! Move your ass!
去 去
Move, move!
- 快快 - 我们走
- Move, move! - Let's go!
- 啊 - 喔 喔 喔
- Ah. - Oh, oh, oh.
我们走 快点
Let's go! Run!
哎呀呀 你们上哪去?
Ay ya ya. Where you going?
- 不 不 不 - 你们要去哪?
- No, no, no! - Where you going?
停车 停车 停车
Stop, stop, stop!
- 别走啊 - 别把汽车人丢下
- Don't leave. - Never leave a bro behind.
啊 震荡波来了
Ah. Shockwave's coming!
快上楼
Go for the stairs!
艾普斯 这边走
Epps, this way!
注意右边 注意右边
Breaking right. Breaking right.
收到 向左
Bead. Rolling in.
又有一个
We got another one coming around.
从左边来了
Coming around on the left side,
注意 右翼也有一个
Ncoming around on the right side.
我们要用威利斯大楼做掩护
We're going to use Willis Tower for cover!
一旦达到高度就往下跳
Once we make altitude, we jump!
- 我们遭到攻击 - 联系总部
- A lot of airplanes out here! - Contact off the nose.
老天 他要坠毁了
Mayday! I don't think he's gonna make it.
6-1号机坠落
Mayday, mayday! Six-one going down.
当心 当心
Heads up! Heads up!
来吧 来吧 来吧
Come on, come on come on.
- 泰利在左边 - 看到目标
- Tally on the left. - Got him.
距离到达目标还有20秒
Got them on target, twenty seconds.
出发 出发
Here we go! Here we go!
集中精力
Keep it tight!
过来了
Coming around.
好了 冲 冲 冲
All right, focus, focus, focus.
敌人在塔正上方
Threat above tower,
六点钟方向
six o'clock!
像蝗虫一样
Locusts!
当心 右边收到攻击
Look out! Breaking right! right!
小心 小心
Watch out, watch out!
噢 该死
Holy shit!
让他们快跳 快跳 快跳
Get them out, get them out, Nget them out!
- 快 出去 出去 - 跳 跳 快跳
- Everybody out, out, out! - Jump, jump, jump!
出去 出去
Get out, get out!
飞起来吧 开始行动
Let's fly, let's move.
让他们全部离机 全部离机
get them all down, get them all down!
救命
Help!
注意分散 散开 散开
Get separation. Track away, track away!
往左转 往左转
Hard left! Hard left!
600英尺
Six hundred feet.
六点钟方向 六点钟方向
Check your six! Check your six!
他在我们后面
He's on our ass!
小心 小心
Watch out, watch out!
急转弯
Sharp right!
大楼在正前方
Building dead ahead!
穿过缺口
Thread the needle!
开伞 开伞
Pull, pull!
快 我们终于到了
Come on, we're high enough!
爬到这里累死人啊
This is a mother getting up here!
- 快把你的肥屁股挪过来 - 来啦
- Get your fat ass over here! - I'm coming.
架上火箭炮
Set up the rocket!
- 快点 - 检查武器
- Come on. - Weapons status?
29把穿透枪
29 Bot-busters,
20把爆裂枪
20 piercing D-Bot.
那里 有穹顶的大厦
There, the building with the dome.
为了牺牲的兄弟们
For our brothers,
我们这次必须成功
let's make this trip worth it.
哦 天啊
Oh, God.
- 这栋楼 - 大楼怎么啦?
- The building! - What building!
该死
shit!
他们正在攻击大楼
They're shooting at the building!
- 这主意可不怎么地 - 什么?
- This is not a good idea. - What?
待在这里不是个好主意
This is not a good idea.
- 这栋楼不稳了 - 听着 先停下来
- This building is not stable. - Listen, stop for a second.
听着 我们要是不尽力一拼
If we don't do what we came to do,
那大家只好一起死
it doesn't matter, we all die.
懂了吗? 看你的了 加油 老兄
Right? That's your target. Come on, man!
楼塌了就完了
I don't even care if the building collapses.
我都要吓出心脏病来了
I'm having a heart attack anyway.
大楼要倒了
The building is going over!
- 稳住 - 找掩体
- Hang on! - Take cover!
抓结实了
Keep your hands up!
好了 停住了
It's okay! It stopped!
你们快看
Guys, look!
别动
Don't move.
来吧
Go, go.
快跑
Run!
火力掩护
Cover fire!
打破玻璃 跳窗
Shoot the glass! Jump out the window!
跳
Jump!
我快玩完了
We're gonna die!
山姆 我停不下来
Sam, I can't stop!
打碎玻璃
Shoot the glass!
山姆
Sam!
- 不不 - 不 不 不
- No, no. - No, no, no.
大家没事吧?
Is everybody okay?
你没事吧?
You okay?
见鬼 那是什么?
What the hell was that?
钻孔机很饿
Driller-bot is thirsty.
那个独眼恶魔正在看着我
This evil thing's looking at me!
什么?
What?
他还带了个蚯蚓一样的霸天虎
It's even got an uglier Decepticon with it!
往回跑
We have to evac!
- 它来了 楼梯被封锁了 - 我们被困住了！
- It's coming up, the stairs are blocked. - We're trapped!
嘿 我们怎么从这里出去?
Hey, how do we get out of here?
嘿 快点
Hey! Come on!
- 不不不 - 噢 上帝 只要让我活着逃出去
- No, no, no. - Oh, Lord Jesus, let me just get out of this alive.
我就把养老金通通都给你
I'll give you annuities, and get it together.
快 得马上撤
Move! We got to move!
霸天虎怎么老是有那么厉害的玩意?
Why do the Decepticons always get the good shit?
- 快跑 - 我们要被吃了
- Move! - We're about to be eaten, people!
我们快要死了
We're gonna die!
撑住
Hold on!
把你的手给我
Give me your hand!
- 我移动到这边 - 抓紧她
- I'm swinging that way! - Got her!
哦 上帝
Oh, my God!
把她丢到防火梯那里
I'm dropping you on the fire escape!
山姆
Sam!
哇 得快离开这里
Whoa, we gotta move!
下去 快跑
Get down, move.
我来救你们了
I'm coming for you!
擎天柱
Optimus!
- 雷霆拯救队 - 我们马上来救你
- Wreckers! - We're coming!
世界各地的霸天虎
Decepticons around the world,
发射能量柱
launch the pillars.
啊 我们太失败了
Ahh, we are so lost.
我们总被大部队落下
Always left out.
太棒了
Ka-ching!
也该轮到咱们无法无天一回了
It's time to lay down the law.
一定要狠狠地揍他们
About to bring some hurt now.
开始了 你看见了吗?
It's starting! You see it?
哇哦 躲起来
Wow! Get down!
山姆和卡莉哪里去了?
Where are Sam and Carly?
这边走
We'll go this way.
我就让你干护送这一件事
I give you one thing to do,
就一件事 这你都能搞砸?
one thing to do, and you drop the ball on that?
你以为我乐意啊?
I ain't signed up for all this!
外星人追着我的屁股不停轰炸
Got aliens blasting at me, running around, chasing me!
还得冒着被倒塌房子砸死的危险
I'm ducking through churches and buildings.
挣扎逃命
and all that kind of crap!
你说这叫什么事啊 我都没法说 艾普斯
This is bullshit! I ain't signed up for this, Epps.
先冷静下来 好吗?
I'm trying to keep it together.
多美妙啊 只有你和我了
What a treat! You and me, alone!
卡莉
Carly!
快 快 快逃
Come on, come on! Run!
他是冲着我来的 不是你
Okay. He's after me, not you.
快跑 快
Wait run, run!
你无处可藏了 小子
You can't hide, boy!
跑
run.
我就喜欢看你们这些小肉虫奔逃时的狼狈样
I just love it whenyour little insect feet try.
逃给我看
to run!
- 山姆 - 跑
- Sam! - Run!
你
you.
还以为你会为我们效命呢 小子
I thought you were working for us, boy?
山姆 山姆
Sam! No!
噢
oh.
我的眼睛
My eye!
目标 霸天虎
Target the Decepticon!
山姆
Sam!
伦诺克斯 你得救救山姆
Lennox, you've got to save Sam!
- 你们得救救他 - 他在搞什么?
- You've got to save him! - What the hell is he doing?
希望这玩意管用
This better work.
钻孔机 钻孔机
D-Bots! D-Bots!
啊 我看不见了 看不见了
Ah...I can't see! I can't see!
山姆 抓住我的手
Sam! It's on my hand!
- 切断绳子 用刀割 不是那样 - 我在试
- Cut the line, cut the line. Not that much. - I'm trying!
割绳 割绳 割绳
The line! The line! The line!
你们这些人渣
You human scum!
- 我们只有20秒 炸弹要爆炸了 - 什么炸弹?
- We got 20 seconds on that bomb! - What bomb?
看见那炸弹没?
You see that bomb?
- 快割 快割 快割 - 知道了
- Cut it, cut it, cut it! - I got it!
我们还有多长时间?
How long do we have?
我要宰了你们
I'm gonna kick you!
割断 割断
Cut, cut, cut!
我要杀了...
I'm gonna kill...
他挂了吧
Well, he's dead.
嘿 现在大黄蜂要去跟其他汽车人汇合
Hey, Bee's going to run withthe rest of the Autobots.
我们到河边去
and meet us at the edge of the river.
好的
All right.
它把我们吸进来了 我也不想这样
It sucked me in! There was nothing I could do!
这下麻烦大了啊
This is a total cluster...
我们必须过河
We got to get across the river.
你看见那个了吗?
You see that?
卡莉说太空桥控制柱就在第一个穹顶里
She said the control pillar was in that first cupola.
好的
All right.
快跑 行动 前进
Let's go! Move! Let's move!
战斧导弹已经发射
Tomahawks are inbound.
预计20分钟后到达
ETA, twenty minutes.
我进入路况监视系统了
I'm in the traffic cameras.
有4名汽车人被俘
Four Autobots are captured.
噢 天哪 我们孤立无援了
Oh, my God. We're helpless.
不管什么情况讯号闪得越来越快
Whatever's set to happen, with those pulses getting faster,
肯定要出事了
it's gonna happen soon.
没有看到擎天柱
No sign of Optimus.
我们怎么才能把这些桥降下来?
How do we get these bridges down?
全体散开 查看情况
Spread out. Check in there.
艾普斯 嘿 艾普斯 还好吗? 你干什么呢?
Epps! Epps, I've been looking for your ass. How you doing?
时间紧迫
Retirement is wack.
更糟的是 我们无法渡河到达那栋大楼
Even worse, we can't get across the river to that building,
而对岸的汽车人全被霸天虎包围了
and the Autobots are upstairs, surrounded.
把镜头转过来一点
Just pan the camera around, all right?
好的 转过来 你来做
All right. Pan... Pan right. That's you.
试着进入大桥主控室
Try getting into the bridge control room.
他们在那里干嘛? 光站着不动?
What are they doing? They're just standing there.
加油 达奇
Hang on. Dutch,
想办法进入大桥主控电脑
see if you can hack into the bridge.
长官 海豹特种部队报到
Sir, SEALs are here.
干得好 小伙子们 你们来了几个人?
It's a good day, boys! What do you got?
10人 为战斧导弹标示打击目标
Got a 10-man SEAL unit, sir, tasked with vectoring Tomahawks.
- 还有多久? - 15分钟
- How long? - Fifteen.
- 你们都是我的俘虏 - 放松点
- You're my prisoners! - Take it easy. We surrender.
别碰我
Get off me.
Get off me!
好了 给你们手中的武器 装填40毫米口径弹药
All right, you're gonna need your40 Mike-Mikes and frags. Go full auto.
切换到自动射击模式 爆炸的震荡波能让它们短路
The vibrations jack up their circuits. Snipers,
狙击手 射瞎他们的眼睛
shoot for the eyes.
目标就在那栋建筑的顶部 现在出击
All right, your target is up on top of that building, that cupola.
你们太愚蠢了 汽车人
How doomed you are, Autobots.
连这么简单的道理都不懂
You simply fail to understand.
少数人的利益
that the needs of the many.
必须服从大众的需求
outweigh the needs of the few.
启动太空桥
Activating the bridge.
他们好像在守卫什么东西
They happy about something.
我们已经到了他们母舰的中心
We're in the heart of their ship.
让咱们帮他们开一会儿
Let's give 'em a little ride.
让我们来把这船掀个底朝天
We gonna screw this ship up.
这是128位的二进制密码
It's a 128K binary encryption code.
很难破解
It's difficult.
但不适用于我 我进去了
But not for me. I'm in.
放下吊桥
Bridge down.
桥面被放下来了
The bridge is coming down!
有人在暗中帮助我们
Someone's watching over us!
快点 快走
Come on! Let's go!
“能跟你合作真是太荣幸了 西摩”
"Pleasure working with you, Seymour".
...我猜你正准备这样说
I believe you're supposed to say.
做得好 达奇
Good job, Dutch.
谢谢夸奖
Danke schoen.
擎天柱 他们正在启动能量柱
Hurry! They're triggering the pillars!
战俘? 你们还收战俘?
Prisoners? You're keeping prisoners?
是的
Yes.
你得教他们学乖点
You need to teach them about respect.
以前是公事公办 现在是私人恩怨 你懂我的意思吗?
This was all business, but now it's personal, do you understand me?
我懂
I understand.
没有战俘
No prisoners,
只有战利品
only trophies.
大黄蜂 我觉得他们想要杀了我们...
Bee, I think they're going to kill us.
你
You,
- 你的死期到了 - 等等 等等
- your time is up. - Wait, wait, wait!
我们投降了
We surrendered!
- 我们是战俘... - 快走
- We're your prisoners. - Move it!
我们就不能谈谈吗?
Can't we talk this out?
我们全都是好小子
We're all a bunch of good chaps!
我是说...
I mean you no...
为什么...
Why did you...
再见了 我的老朋友
Good-bye, my old friend.
现在 你是我的了
You're mine now.
别碰我
Get off me!
我得去救他
I got to help him.
什么?
What?
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我要去救他
I got to help him.
你救不了的
you can't help him.
山姆
Sam.
转过身去
Turn around.
我们...我们永别了
We... We gave 'em a hell of a run.
成功了 小诸葛 我们成功了
We did it, Brains! We did it!
把飞船拆成废铁吧
Rip this ship apart!
- 我们干得真棒 小诸葛 你和我 - 是啊
- We had a nice run, Brains, you and me. - Yeah.
不过我们死定了
we gonna die.
哇 哇 哇
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
好了 宝贝 跟我们一起来吧
Okay, baby! You all come with us!
我们走 你们跟紧地面部队 走
Go! You guys, follow that ground team! Go!
快 快 快走
Move, move, move!
艾普斯 你们上3楼 我们要上45楼
Epps, third floor! We're going to 45!
你们两个狙击手留在这里
All right. Two snipers, right here!
好 报告位置
All right, dock up!
3分钟后就跳伞
We jump in three minutes!
安置火力点 这边
Set the shot, right here.
好 各就各位
All right, set up.
在楼下
I'm downstairs.
有5个目标 还有震荡波 就在我们脚下
We got five targets and Shockwave right below us.
准备跳伞
Stand by to jump!
好了 我们走 准备 准备
All right, let's go! Get ready, get ready.
好 跳
Go, move.
狙击手 敲了他们的眼睛
Snipers, take out their eyes.
爆破组 安装炸弹
All right, demo team, let's crank steel.
即时引爆
Turning steel!
他妈的
Holy shit.
没我命令不准开火
Don't fire till I tell you!
快
Go!
干得不错 小子
Good job, kid!
开火
Fire!
- 我们打倒他了 - 是啊
- We got him! - Yeah!
包围
He's on the run!
汽车人 攻击
Autobots, attack!
火力集中到桥上
Mortar that bridge!
现在这是我们的世界了
It's our world now!
开始传送
Commence transport!
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
擎天柱
Optimus!
去死吧
You die!
不
No!
给我下来 御天敌
Get down here, Sentinel!
擎天柱
Optimus,
你忘了你的立场
you forget your place!
我给你带来了塞伯坦
I bring you Cybertron,
你的故乡
your home.
你依然要站在人类那边吗?
and still you choose humanity.
是你教会我“自由权利归众生”
You were the one who taught me freedom is everyone's right.
我会重启能量柱
I will retrigger that pillar!
那你得先过我这关
Then you'll have to go through me!
听着 我得去帮忙
Okay, I've got to try and help.
- 别 别去 - 我自己去 你留在这里
- Don't you go. Don't go. - I have to. You stay here.
你会没事的
You'll be fine,
- 我保证 - 你得答应我
- Okay? - I promise.
我得到主控能量柱那去
I got to get to that pillar.
拿下能量柱
Charge the pillar!
汽车人来了
We got Autobots!
我需要支援
Reinforcements!
霸天虎 向擎天柱开火
Decepticon ships, fire at Optimus!
发射 我现在就需要那些战斧导弹
We're taking fire! I need those Tomahawks now!
第一波导弹即将到达
First wave inbound.
我们必须掩护擎天柱
We've got to cover for Optimus!
霸天虎 夺回能量柱
Decepticons, trigger the pillar!
重启能量柱
Restart that pillar!
启动那根能量柱
Trigger the pillars.
我挡不住了
I can't hold them!
我需要闪一下
The ships have us pinned!
不
No!
离导弹到达还有10秒
Inbound, 10 seconds! Danger close!
解码 重复 重复14250
Mark-Lima-Echo-Echo, 14250!
- 指示收到 - 请给座标
- Positive surface contact. - Target I. D.
已获取目标
Target acquired.
迪伦
Dylan!
- 等等 - 不
- Wait! - No!
迪伦
Dylan!
住手 住手
Stop! Stop!
不
No!
你不能这样做
You can't do this,
好吗?
okay?
对我来说只有一个未来
There's only one future for me.
塞伯坦 你终于得救了...
Cybertron, you are saved,
在最后时刻
...at last.
哦 你是来向我投降的吗?
Oh, have you come to surrender?
- 这一切都值得吗? - 当然了
- Was it all worth it? - Obviously.
你费尽心机救回了御天敌
All your work to bring Sentinel back.
而现在他却夺走了你所有的权力
and now clearly he has all the power.
我都有点替你感到难过了
It's actually almost tragic.
你胆敢教训我 奴隶?
You dare lecture me, slave?
就算你的霸天虎最终征服这个星球
Your Decepticons finally conquering this planet,
他们的超级领袖也不会是你
and yet, their leader won't be you!
一定是我 永远是我
It will be me! It will always be me.
再过个几分钟
In any minute now,
你就什么都不是了 只是个御天敌的奴才
you'll be nothing but Sentinel's bitch.
再发射
Again!
死!
Die!
你在选阵营时
You chose sides?
选错了
You chose wrong.
你一直是我们中最勇敢的战士
Always the bravest of us!
但你总是无法做出艰难抉择
But you could never make the hard decisions!
现在
Now...
我们的星球会生存下去
Our planet will survive!
不
No!
我们曾经是神 我们全都是
We were gods once. All of us.
但在这里...
But here...
求你住手
Please!
神只能有一个
...there will only be one!
这是我的星球
This is my planet!
我刚刚拯救了另一个世界
I just saved a whole other world.
你以为你是英雄?
You think you're a hero, huh?
你以为你是个英雄吗?
You think you're a hero?
不
No.
我只不过是个送信的
I'm just a messenger.
太空桥仍然连接着
The pillar's still connected!
小心点 等等
Watch, wait up!
- 大黄蜂 - 快走 快走
- Bee! - Let's go, let's go!
- 我们一起做吧 - 快点 快
- Let's do this! - Move, move!
它仍在运作
Pillar's still connected!
摧毁那根能量柱
Rip that pillar down!
不...
No...
我们应该停战
we need a truce.
我只不过想重掌领导权
All I want is to be back in charge.
此外
Besides,
没有我你能做什么
who would you be without me,
擎天柱?
Prime?
咱们走着瞧
Time to find out.
擎天柱 我所想要的 不过是我们种族的延续
Optimus, all I ever wanted was the survival of our race.
你必须明白 我不得不背叛你的原因
You must see why I had to betray you.
你并没有背叛我
You didn't betray me.
你背叛了你自己
You betrayed yourself.
不 擎天柱
No, Optimus!
山姆
Sam.
- 我爱你 - 我爱你
- I love you. - I love you.
在这世上我只需要你
You're the only thing I need in this world,
我会为你做任何事 我保证
and I'll do anything to make it up to you, I promise.
你可要信守承诺
I'm going to hold you to that.
不要再放我走了
Just never let me go.
我保证
I promise.
戒指?
Rings.
我爱这辆车
I love this car.
大黄蜂 你得悠着点
Bee, you've got to slow it down.
悠着点来 好吗?
You got to slow way down, okay?
我只想帮个忙 老兄
I'm just trying to help out.
战争之中
In any war.
总会有暴风雨之间的平静
there are calms between storms.
你小子很勇敢
You fought bravely.
有时候我们会失去信念
There will be days when we lose faith.
有时候我们的盟友会背叛我们
Days when our allies turn against us.
但是我们绝对不会放弃地球
But the day will never come that we forsake this planet.
和地球上的人类
and its people.
哥的美好未来就从这一刻开始了
That's what I call the start of a beautiful future.
逮捕他
Arrest him.
那也值
It was worth it!
把他带走
Get him out of here!
哥愿为爱坐牢 哥不在乎
I'd go to jail for love! I don't care!
嘿 抓我吧 哥想坐牢 哥想进去
Hey! Take me in! I want to go in! Let's go in.
快点 夏洛特 快把哥抓起来
Come on, Charlotte, take me in right now!